<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged Tajikistan</title>
<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/tags/Tajikistan/"/>
<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/tags/Tajikistan/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Team Geekout (Jamie&Kai) geeked out on the Mongol Rally 2011</name>

</author>




<id>https://geekout.org.uk/tags/Tajikistan/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Team Geekout (Jamie&amp;Kai) geeked out on the Mongol Rally 2011</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2011-08-27T06:47:43Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>Khorog</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Khorog/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Khorog/"/>






	<category term="Tajikistan" />

	<category term="kai" />


	<updated>2011-08-27T06:47:43Z</updated>
	<published>2019-08-31T06:46:10Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/6085126222/&quot; title=&quot;Pamir camp by Kai Hendry, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6086/6085126222_98e7d5efea.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;374&quot; alt=&quot;Pamir camp&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After camping near Kevron (where the M41 hits Afghanistan) on quite a nice spot
on the River (Afghanistan a stone throw away), we woke up to drive to
&lt;a href=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Tajikistan/&quot;&gt;Horugh&lt;/a&gt; which is also known as Khorog, depending on how the
Cyrillic is transliterated (so annoying).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were feeling pretty bad because we were supposed to be in Khorog that night
in order to keep to the plan to do the Pamirs in just 3 days in order not to
overrun our Tajikistan visa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we finally arrived in Khorog around lunch we were delighted that we caught
up with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://mud-lab.com/&quot;&gt;Icelanders&lt;/a&gt; who we&#39;ve hung out before in
Turkmenistan. We were convinced they were a day ahead of us, so we were really
surprised we somehow caught up with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also came across an Ambulance rally team who were stuck in Khorog because of
some repairs they needed. They said they predicted they would only be in Almaty
on the 2nd of September (last Mongol Rally party is on the 3rd in UB). All this
time I had thought we were running incredibly late. I&#39;m writing this
from Almaty and we plan on leaving on the 29th, so we are days and days ahead
of that convoy we came across in the Pamirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we hastily pushed on east on the Pamir in convoy with Thor, Gunnar &amp;amp; Ale,
and we made good progress. The roads were actually quite alright, it was only
the first stretch around Khist where it was crazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn&#39;t make Murgarb and by nightfall but we found a &quot;Yurt hotel&quot; and agreed
on 50USD for 5 of us to sleep there, including a dinner of Plov and a breakfast of 
slightly sour, undercooked rice pudding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve never stayed in a yurt before, though after freezing my ass off in there
with a bit of altitude sickness (we were at 4200m+), I must say I am not keen
on ever staying in a yurt again. Our hostess was very nice, but it was clear to
me she was extremely poor so the food et al was pretty unsophisciated and
meagre by my snobbish standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we made a bid for the border in order not to overrun our visa.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Khorog/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Khorog/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Tajikistan</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Tajikistan/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Tajikistan/"/>






	<category term="Tajikistan" />

	<category term="kai" />


	<updated>2011-08-27T05:04:30Z</updated>
	<published>2019-08-31T06:46:10Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;After being frankly disappointed by Samarqand town, I was looking forward to
getting into Tajkistan to do the Pamirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We crossed from Denov from the south as advised by our kind host Zafar.
Unfortunately the direct border has been closed from 2001. So it was quite a
long drive and thankfully we did find a place with petrol along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first time we looked close at our Tajik visas and my heart sank as I
saw the visa expires on the 24th and it was the 21st. I allocated 1 week in my
mind to do Pamirs, there was no way we could do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Uzbek/Tajik border near Denov was probably our quickest, but we had to pay
10USD bribe / dodgy admin fee and the car insurance seemed to be negotiable
from 45USD down to 25USD. All very silly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting into Dashunbe in darkness was not so bad, since there was good car I
followed all the way into town. I was copying his every move and flinch through
pot-holed roads. Next finding the recommended hostel &quot;Adventurer&#39;s Inn&quot; must have
consumed a good hour, but we found it after a taxi driver rode with us for
5USD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then tried to get some food which always seems to be a chore. Everyone
eats at sundown and then seemingly closes up. Nonetheless we ordered an
expensive Chinese take out, which later transpired could have fed four.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jamie chatted to the English and rag tag bunch of &quot;adventurers&quot; in the Inn.
Most if not all were cycling or motorbiking the Pamirs. Although many of them
took weeks if not an entire month, though they all agreed we could do it in
the time we had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Down south from Dushanbe to Kulob, up and around to Horugh should take 15hrs (22nd)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Horugh to Murghab (23rd)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mughab to the Kyrgyz border for the 24th (the same day the visa expires)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tbh I previously thought Osh was in Tajikistan, so I agreed to this plan.
Previously I assumed we had to go straight up to Kyrgystan to avoid
over-running our visa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Pamirs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/6087820791/&quot; title=&quot;Road Clearage by Jamie Kitson, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6070/6087820791_ebc493f782_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;159&quot; alt=&quot;Road Clearage&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we woke early. Jamie had a bad night sleep as there weren&#39;t any free beds
that night. I had the shits all night, so I pledged I would not eat meat again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/6088367502/&quot; title=&quot;Snooze by Jamie Kitson, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6084/6088367502_a596213dd0_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;159&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; alt=&quot;Snooze&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The long drive to the Pamir Highway itself, from Dushanbe through Kulob, turned
out to be some of the most spectacular driving, possibly even more so than the
the traditional M41 Pamir highway itself. It started winding up and down bigger
and bigger hills, eventually turning into very colourful mountains and sheer
drops.  The going was fairly slow, as we were quite concious of the terrible
condition of the road and our tiny front wheel drive car. We even had to stop
while a very large landslide was cleared by some heavy machinery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached the Pamir proper, where there is a roaring river separating
Afghanistan and Tajikistan, and it was stunning.  The road was quite
challenging at first, then we later got used it and in fact started to enjoy
it.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Tajikistan/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Tajikistan/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>

</feed>
