<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>pages tagged Uzbekistan</title>
<link>https://geekout.org.uk/tags/Uzbekistan/</link>
<atom:link href="https://geekout.org.uk/tags/Uzbekistan/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<description>Team Geekout (Jamie&amp;Kai) geeked out on the Mongol Rally 2011</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2011 19:02:12 +0100</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>The Mongol Rally is actually a bit of a jolly</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geekout.org.uk/posts/The_Mongol_Rally_is_actually_a_bit_of_a_jolly/</guid>

	<link>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/The_Mongol_Rally_is_actually_a_bit_of_a_jolly/</link>



	<category>Uzbekistan</category>

	<category>jamie</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 07:46:10 +0100</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-08-20T18:02:12Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;We had a really good day today, despite some really depressing news last night.
As Kai wrote, yesterday we crossed into Uzbekistan, which was probably one of
the least pleasant border crossings yet, but still the hardest bit is remaining
patient. However last night I happened to check my emails, the first time in a
while as internet was really hard to come by in Turmenistan, and Team America
had emailed warning that the Uzbek border guards had been wondering where we
were as we had &quot;missed a step&quot;, and needed to go back to get our &quot;yellow form&quot;.
As we&#39;d left I did wonder how come we still had both copies of our customs
declaration forms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we made the decision this morning to go back. I was in more of a mind to
risk it, but Kai has become risk-averse of late. Good thing too. It was also
lucky that we hadn&#39;t gone all the way to Samarqant as I had suggested as there
would have been no way we would have wanted to drive back the 700 odd km to the
border. (To be honest Buxoro was nicer to visit than Samarqant anyway.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after a few last trips to the toilet in our water-less hostel, we left at
about 8:30am and made good progress, getting back to the border at about
9:30am. In contrast to the day before the border was very quiet and we got back
to the customs office easily. There the two male and female guards recognised
us, pretended to be cross with us, told us that we must thank the friends who
notified us as we would now be able to leave the country, and sent us on our
way. The guards outside were a bit annoyed when I played with their attack dog,
it was so cute, but still didn&#39;t have any water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then made quick time back to Buxoro for a very good lunch (I opted for beef
shashlik again, as it was so good last night. Kai&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pilaf&quot;&gt;plov&lt;/a&gt; was very good too,
which I was surprised at) stopping only to see if we could get some fuel from
one of the very few open petrol stations which all have very long queues
outside. I walked down to check that they had 95 octane &quot;benzene&quot; and we were
waved in, past all the locals (sorry locals).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made it to Samarqand for about 6, stopping once so that Kai could take a dip
in a very grey/brown fast flowing river, which we had a job getting him out of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully tomorrow we will make it to and through the Tajik border, stay the
night and start the Pamir Highway on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we started this trip I was a bit concerned as Kai was always talking
about two months, while my work had given me 6-7 weeks. Once we started however
it was me who was suggesting we spend a bit more time in, for instance, Iran,
and Kai was then getting nervous about being left behind by the rest of the
ralliers. When we left Iran I was quite happy with our progress as we&#39;d done
about 6500 miles in three and a bit weeks and only had about 2000 left to go.
However, one day into Turkmenistan, driving to Mary, and I realised how a bad
road can turn your 800km days into 200km days and so many small countries means
the border crossings start to eat up time and I began to get nervous. Since
Mary the roads have been much better, hopefully they  won&#39;t get too bad, else I
might have to leave Kai to finish the rally on his own &lt;img src=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/smileys/smile4.png&quot; alt=&quot;;)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


	<comments>/posts/The_Mongol_Rally_is_actually_a_bit_of_a_jolly/#comments</comments>

</item>
<item>
	<title>The Mongol Rally is actually quite hard</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geekout.org.uk/posts/The_Mongol_Rally_is_actually_quite_hard/</guid>

	<link>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/The_Mongol_Rally_is_actually_quite_hard/</link>



	<category>Uzbekistan</category>

	<category>kai</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 07:46:10 +0100</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-08-20T18:02:12Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m drunk and emotional as I write this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who only have a few weeks left of their life, then I recommend the
Mongol Rally. It&#39;s full of life experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m getting a bit emotional, especially as we met the Italian team &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/highwaytokhan&quot;&gt;Highway to
Kahn&lt;/a&gt; over beers in Samarqand [rhymes with
TravelPussy]. Jamie and I took quite an intrepid route like many other
ralliers, to the south through Iran. Getting through Iran and Turkmenistan
especially is not easy let me tell you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore we have the Pamir Highway to do, which some other teams aren&#39;t doing. So
this adds a week to our itinerary. Especially since we have now discovered there
is no direct crossing between Samarkand and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dushanbe&quot;&gt;Dushanbe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many very hard days of planning, driving and finding accommodation
ahead of us. Even if things go well, we predict we will be in Mongolia around
the ~12th of September. More than a week after the last Finish line party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really hope we don&#39;t have a massive anti-climax once we reach Ulanbataar. We are
really working very very hard on finishing and we hope we get some recognition
from at least our friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


	<comments>/posts/The_Mongol_Rally_is_actually_quite_hard/#comments</comments>

</item>
<item>
	<title>Turkmenabat and Bukhara</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Turkmenabat_and_Bukhara/</guid>

	<link>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Turkmenabat_and_Bukhara/</link>



	<category>Uzbekistan</category>

	<category>kai</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 07:46:10 +0100</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-08-19T14:21:25Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;After Mary we though we could cross the border at Turkmenabat that day, though
we decided to have a look at Merv. There was an old hill that was once a
settlement in 100AD or something, though the area was quite nice. Just lacking
some good information about it, since we were without Internet or a guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way to Turkmenabat Jamie and I hit a low point. Jamie got the car stuck
on sand and the people helped us out of us then demanded money for their
generosity. Not cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time we approached Turkmenabat at 5-6pm, it was far too late to cross
the border. We then spent another hour or two trying to find a hotel. We
eventually found the LP recommend one, but they said we must go to the new
Jehun hotel. This is typical Turkmenistan weirdness. Foreigners are denied a
stay in any hotel. Also it&#39;s quite hard to get A-95 fuel, unless you&#39;re a VIP
or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the hotel we found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rallyteamamerica.com/&quot;&gt;Team America&lt;/a&gt; who had been hanging around for hours they
claim which we found surprising and a little depressing since we honestly tried
to push that day. Nonetheless we enjoyed Lex &amp;amp; Jeff&#39;s company, whilst geeking
out with a few beers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day (today), we aimed for the border. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rallyteamamerica.com/&quot;&gt;Team America&lt;/a&gt; had to fill up, so
we had a head start. The border experience was once again a kafka-esque
experience that I&#39;m trying to forget. Firstly it was near impossible to &lt;em&gt;find
the border&lt;/em&gt; since there were no signs. We had to pay a small &quot;fine&quot; on the
Uzbek side since Jamie drove through the disinfectant pool too fast, which was
not true. We were at the border for over four hours and strangely we didn&#39;t see
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rallyteamamerica.com/&quot;&gt;Team America&lt;/a&gt;. I wonder where they are. We did bump into the Mongolian team
again, which was nice. They escaped Turkmenistan by paying a 42USD fine for
overstaying their visa, since they were waiting for their Uzbek visa.
&lt;strong&gt;Nightmare&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally I&#39;m here in Bukhara, home of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Great_Game&quot;&gt;Great
Game&lt;/a&gt;. We&#39;re in the old city which
feels like a bit of an oasis. A few French tourists, another Mongol Rally car
and sweet Internet. Roaming on my mobile also works to great relief. It wasn&#39;t
working on the border.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[There was one positive to take from the Uzbek border crossing, it was the first
border where I had to use a visa in my old passport. The guards just laughed at
me. One down, three to go. Jamie]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ps, Team America have just emailed to say that we missed a step and the border guards were saying that we should go back :-/]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


	<comments>/posts/Turkmenabat_and_Bukhara/#comments</comments>

</item>

</channel>
</rss>
