<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged Jamie</title>
<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/tags/Jamie/"/>
<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/tags/Jamie/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Team Geekout (Jamie&Kai) geeked out on the Mongol Rally 2011</name>

</author>




<id>https://geekout.org.uk/tags/Jamie/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Team Geekout (Jamie&amp;Kai) geeked out on the Mongol Rally 2011</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>A Message To Our Sponsors</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/A_Message_To_Our_Sponsors/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/A_Message_To_Our_Sponsors/"/>






	<category term="jamie" />

	<category term="sponsorship" />


	<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
	<published>2011-09-12T09:09:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;letter&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hello!
&lt;p&gt;
First of all thank you very much for your sponsorship, it was much
appreciated by Kai and I as it allowed us to get off on our little
jaunt, and I&#39;m sure it will be appreciated almost as much by our two
charities, Amnesty International and the Christina Noble Children&#39;s
Foundation in Mongolia. The current total is £1570, though since we&#39;ve
finished we&#39;ve had a small flurry of donations.
&lt;p&gt;
Now on to what you have all been waiting for, the results! We arrived
at the finish line at approximately 4:57pm Mongolia time on Thursday
8th September, which I make 6 weeks, 4 days, 18 hours and 57 minutes,
having done 12,566 miles, or 20,223 km.
&lt;p&gt;
In the distance guess Rachel gets a special mention, as the only
person to overestimate, however we didn&#39;t quite hit the 30,000 mile
mark I&#39;m afraid Rachel. Claudio&#39;s guess of 8425 miles was just pipped
by Sara and Rob&#39;s guess of 8454.4 miles. As Claudio said, we certainly
did more miles than planned.
&lt;p&gt;
In the time guess Larry and Gez both predicted 4th September, just
four days off, but my sister Maddy (Sara and Rob&#39;s niece, keeping it
in the family) managed a guess just 16 hours out!
&lt;p&gt;
Prizes will be distributed to those two lucky, or skilled, winners,
but if the rest of you would like to send me your address I will post
you a (very small) token of our appreciation.
&lt;p&gt;
The rally itself went pretty well for us, if you haven&#39;t been keeping
up our blog is at https://geekout.org.uk/ and a map of our trip is
here: https://geekout.org.uk/map/
&lt;p&gt;
Back to work for me tomorrow.
&lt;p&gt;
Thanks again, Jamie
&lt;/div&gt;
If you&#39;ve enjoyed our updates, and haven&#39;t already, maybe it&#39;s time to think about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justgiving.com/teams/geekout/&quot;&gt;donating&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/A_Message_To_Our_Sponsors/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/A_Message_To_Our_Sponsors/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Unofficial Payments</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Unofficial_Payments/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Unofficial_Payments/"/>






	<category term="bribes" />

	<category term="jamie" />


	<updated>2012-06-25T09:45:45Z</updated>
	<published>2011-09-11T03:05:26Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;ie, Bribes. The best technique seems to be waiting for a) official boredom, b) more money making opportunities to turn up, eg, tourists c) somebody higher up in the chain to come along, eg, military vs police.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Country&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Asked for&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Paid&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ukraine&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;€100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;€30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Supposedly doing 80kph in a 50kph zone. Possibly true.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ukraine&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;€40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;€20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Not stopping at a stop sign. The trouble was there was a massive truck in the way of the sign, if there was a sign.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Iran&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Multiool (€30)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T-shirt and tea&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Official at the border kept asking for gifts. Wished we hadn&#39;t given him anything after below.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Iran&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;€20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;€10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Burly man at the border who we didn&#39;t want to piss off too much.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Iran&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Caught speeding, but let off with a warning &lt;img src=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Turkmenistan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Caught speeding as the police put up temporary speed limit signs, in this case 30kph, which was honestly difficult to read.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Uzbekistan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This was actually official, I even got a receipt! But it was still ridiculous. I was fined for driving too quickly through the &quot;disinfectant&quot; at the border. There was no way I caused all the puddles that they were pointing at, tbh, I think the team that went before me might have done it, but we both got fined. We didn&#39;t stop at the stop sign, a recurring theme.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Uzbekistan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;£1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kai caught speeding. Let off after trying out speed gun and a misunderstanding about a &quot;gift&quot;, Kai insisted on going back and giving him a souvenir pound coin. The policeman did not look impressed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Passport officials. Stupidly paid without thinking.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Car insurance, or possibly customs. I think $25 was the proper sum, but we were asked for $45.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Have a feeling that the last two guys that dealt with us wanted something?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Police check at the border. I was going to the car to get some money but they got bored and we just left.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Up to €100 down to $20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Police check point just looking for a reason to take money from us. First they made something up about our visas. We were patient and explained again and again that our visas were ok. When they got bored of that they let Mud-Lab go and started on me and my invalid passport. They were just insisting on $20 when a military guy walked passed outside and they suddenly took our $10 and let us go. I kind of wished I&#39;d snatched the $10, run outside and waved it in their face from the window. But I didn&#39;t.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;


&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$25 x 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10 for both cars.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Customs leaving Tajikistan. This seemed to be a tried and trusted scam, telling us that we were missing the customs receipt from entering (see above). It may even be that customs delierately didn&#39;t give us a receipt when we entered. We were let off for $10 only when two more teams arrived and were subjected to the same treatment.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kyrgyzstan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Thought I&#39;d mention this as I was very pleased not to be asked at the border as the guards were looking very serious and very dubious about the visa in my old, invalid passport.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kyrgyzstan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10 + 100 Somme ($3?)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kai caught speeding early in the morning, apparently still within the limits of a town.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kyrgyzstan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;All our old Uzbek money, about $20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Caught speeding again, same day.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kyrgyzstan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10 between two cars&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Same day. Not stopping at a stop sign, *just* before the Kazakh border.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kazakhstan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Accidentally left border into Kazakhstan and needed to get back in to Kai and the car. Was brazenly asked for $10 but didn&#39;t pay and met Kai outside.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Russia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;100 Rubles I think, about $3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Immigration officer just asked as we were leaving, we acted confused and after a few minutes let us go.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mongolia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;100 Rubles, about $3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;For disinfecting the car. Other teams said they had to pay $1 and got a receipt.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mongolia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The guy who searched our car (with a very cute dog in a very cute coat) just asked, and we just gave.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Total&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;About $310&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;About $180&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;/table&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Unofficial_Payments/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Unofficial_Payments/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Altay to Bayankhongor&#44; Mongolia</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Altay_to_Bayankhongor__44___Mongolia/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Altay_to_Bayankhongor__44___Mongolia/"/>






	<category term="jamie" />

	<category term="mongolia" />


	<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
	<published>2011-09-07T04:19:42Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;We travelled for most of the day in convoy with the five other teams, having
fun with the driving, sliding around and racing each other. Micras are
definitely well suited to Mongolian roads, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mud-lab.com&quot;&gt;Mud Lab&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s 1.6L
Peugeot 306 the only one able to keep up with the two Micras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch Kai and I and Mud Lab broke away from the four other teams and made
it into Altay, Mud Lab running low on both fuel and money. We milled around in the town for a bit, picking up some supplies
&amp;amp; money, Mud Lab making some more repairs. This time, worryingly, to their
brakes, having already had to fix a fuel leak on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided I was tired of noodles and fancied eating in a restaurant. A helpful
gentleman said, through a translator on the phone, that he would show us a place.
He got in our car and we literally drove around the block. He showed us a restaurant.
The guy on the phone then said we should give him 15,000 of the local currency.
Reluctantly I did. He refused asking for 20,000. By this time Kai was still sitting
in the drivers seat, but I was out of the car and the guy was blocking my way.
Eventually Kai started to drive off, I jumped in the front seat and we sped off back
to Mud Lab. Considering that it was just around the corner we were concerned that
we might have an angry Mongolian or two on our tail and were rather put off Altay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kai and I decided to go ahead and scout out potential camp sites, but when we found
how cold and windy it was went back into town to have a look at hotels. We weren&#39;t
impressed and together with Mud Lab and their newly working brakes headed out. We
aimed for what we thought could be a natural wind break over a hill, but managed to
end up in a natural wind tunnel. It started to rain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day was slow going, partially due to the bad roads, but mostly due to
Mud Lab&#39;s bad luck. (Or perhaps poor planing in choosing a Peugeot  ;).) After a
couple of hours driving they sailed over a ridge and hit the other side, blew
both airbags, dislodging their front grill and fan. As they couldn&#39;t reattach
the fan their car started to overheat at regular intervals and they would have
to stop and point their car straight into the wind for a while. Moments after
one of these stops they discovered one of their tyres had split.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards evening the wind was really getting up, causing something like a dust
storm, as we approached a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yurt&quot;&gt;gher&lt;/a&gt; camp and &lt;a
href=&quot;https://maps.google.co.uk/?ll=45.833584,99.372368&amp;amp;spn=0.072121,0.181789&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;z=13&amp;amp;vpsrc=6&quot;&gt;large
river&lt;/a&gt;. Looking at our maps it seemed that the road was on the other side of
the river. Several locals pointed us in the direction of the river and one
offered to tow us across in his tractor for $30 each. We were dubious and
waited. After a while a mini bus approached and we followed it, watching as it
crossed the river, from one island to another. We followed in its footsteps. It
was pretty nerve racking to be honest, especially as there were about four
crossings in total, two of which we hadn&#39;t seen the mini bus cross, but we made
it. I really regret not taking a picture of what greeted us, a desolate,
apocalyptic even, vision of dust caught by the sun blowing across several ghers
and virtually nothing else for as far as the eye could see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this time there was only an hour or two of sunlight left, and we&#39;d only done
about 250km of 400km, but we decided to press on. The roads got even worse and
our speed slowed and slowed as night drew in, and the wind got colder. About
40km from Bayankhongor the road started to get quite wet and muddy. About 10km
from town Mud Lab looked like they got stuck in mud. Their car sounded like it
wasn&#39;t quite in gear. Ale reckons they might have a broken Axel. We managed to
tow them out of the worst of the mud they were in, but didn&#39;t think we&#39;d make
it the 10km due to the mud, we were having difficulty getting just ourselves
out of some of it. So we left them there and went to get help. Practically over
the next hill we were able to see the lights of the town and had mobile signal
and were able to call the Adventurists hot line, but by the time we got back to
Mud Lab to give them the good news they&#39;d already managed to get a tow from a
Mongolian mining magnate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kai and I visited several hotels before picking one we liked and were just
checking in when who should turn up but Mud Lab!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was last night. We woke this morning, opened the curtains and thanked our
lucky stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s snowing!&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Altay_to_Bayankhongor__44___Mongolia/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Altay_to_Bayankhongor__44___Mongolia/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Khovd to Altay&#44; Mongolia</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Khovd_to_Altay__44___Mongolia/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Khovd_to_Altay__44___Mongolia/"/>






	<category term="jamie" />

	<category term="mongolia" />


	<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
	<published>2011-09-05T11:54:19Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Driving in Mongolia is a lot of fun. The roads tend to be very wide, usually gravelly, or if
you&#39;re really lucky very sandy and often splitting off into 2, 3 or even six different paths.
There are often obstacles, some of them moving, including camels, stones and various types of
holes, dips and ridges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent our second night in Mongolia in a gher camp setup by one of the
Mongolians actually doing the rally in Khovd. It was to be the last night of
his camp and he had already taken down most of the ghers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we started the long drive to Altay, apparently the worst bit of the Southern route
across Mongolia. I may be tempting fate here, but it really hasn&#39;t been that bad so far, more
of the above. The worst is the small, regular ridges, possibly caused by tracked vehicles in the
winter. The cars vibrate painfully, until you reach the &lt;em&gt;Sweet Spot&lt;/em&gt;. Usually at about 90kph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To our great pleasure We&#39;d met the Icelandic team, Mud Lab, yet again, in Khovd
and left with them in the morning, east. In the evening we came across two other
teams, Modern Nomads (Kit from Norway) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://hittheroadyak.com/&quot;&gt;Hit the Road
Yak&lt;/a&gt; (George and Matt) and then another two teams
that they&#39;d been in convoy with, Fear and Alexes in Mongolia (Alex, whose team
mate had had to fly to Ulan bater to get a rabies jab after being bitten by a
dog in Khovd) and &lt;a
href=&quot;https://mongolrally2011.blogspot.com/2011/09/days-forty-six-and-forty-seven-never-be.html&quot;&gt;Banana
Hammock (Heather and Justin)&lt;/a&gt;, which made six teams in total, the largest
convoy we&#39;ve travelled with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I would like to to treat the next bit like an episode of Casualty, what could possibly go wrong
in the following situation?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The four teams we&#39;d met had this game they played, called rocky rock, where
they would all throw stones at a specific rock, trying to hit it. A little
while after starting this game, &lt;s&gt;someone, George I think,&lt;/s&gt; Alex aimed a small rock at
Kit&#39;s car, hitting the back window and shattering it. Like all good geeks, he
fixed it with duct tape. Taping up the whole window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moved on. We were one of the last cars. Just after a particular sandy
section of road we found Kit and his car, pointing in the wrong direction. He&#39;d
spun and both left tyres had deflated, he decided due to the seal being broken
rather than punctures. Luckily he had two spares, changed them with us watching
and we were on our way. The other teams had stopped up ahead to camp and we
formed a bit of a circle with our wagons. Kit was determined to make a fire and
started chopping up a bit of wood he had with an axe. We joked that with the
luck he&#39;d had he shouldn&#39;t be wielding an axe.  Kit gathered some dung and
asked for some petrol. Being as my mum has always drummed into me not to use
petrol on fires I didn&#39;t volunteer our petrol and hoped he could find something
a little less flammable. The next thing we knew he was opening a very large
jerry can in the middle of the circle. For some reason the can was pressurised
and very full and sprayed petrol as it was opened.  Unfortunately one team had
already started cooking and in the moment that we all stood, staring in
disbelief the petrol ignited. Now Hollywood (and Casualty) may have lead you to
believe that the petrol on the ground will burn in a nice line until it reaches
the full can at which point the can will explode and everyone dies. Let me tell
you from experience that this is not what happens.  The spilt petrol all
ignited simultaneously, everyone ran for their lives and then there was a calm
moment as everything just burned. Luckily none of the petrol had reached the
car. Unfortunately Kit had been sprayed and was now on fire. &lt;s&gt;Someone, George I
believe&lt;/s&gt; Alex, redeeming himself from breaking Kit&#39;s back windscreen managed to put
Kit out and the rest of us stood in shock. Kai was the first to remember that
we actually had a fire extinguisher and handed it to me, later saying that he
didn&#39;t want to be the one caught in any explosion.  Kit&#39;s burns didn&#39;t seem too
bad, though obviously relatively serious and apparently very painful. Kit
happened to have set his video camera up on a tripod and filmed the whole
thing. Several of us wondered if he&#39;d done the whole thing on purpose &lt;img src=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/smileys/smile4.png&quot; alt=&quot;;)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Khovd_to_Altay__44___Mongolia/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Khovd_to_Altay__44___Mongolia/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Kazakhstan Into Russia</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Kazakhstan_Into_Russia/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Kazakhstan_Into_Russia/"/>






	<category term="Kazakhstan" />

	<category term="Russia" />

	<category term="jamie" />


	<updated>2011-10-29T19:08:37Z</updated>
	<published>2011-08-31T11:09:58Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;We just made the Kazakhstan/Russia border by night fall. It was a little windy
and some of the coldest weather we&#39;ve experienced since Europe. The Kazakh
guards were all very friendly, and unusually thorough.  Our car got its first
semi-decent search, they got us to take everything out of the boot and even had
a look at the spare, though not really checking the rest of the car. As ever
they asked beforehand if we were carrying any heroin. We proceeded to passport
control where my two passports were given even more attention than normal.
Slowly more and more senior officials were called, until a small huddle formed,
all looking at my passports in puzzled silence, as if they were trying to crack
a particularly hard maths problem or crossword clue. The trouble is, once
they&#39;ve decided there&#39;s a problem they can&#39;t really just let you through
without loosing face, you have to come up with some new piece of evidence for
them to go &quot;Aaaah, that&#39;s ok then.&quot; Eventually I pointed out, for the second
time, that upon entering the country I&#39;d had both my visa (in my old passport)
stamped &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; my new passport stamped, and we were on our way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russia is a serious country and I was expecting a serious border, but it was
actually one of the easiest entries we&#39;ve had. &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; easiest I would say, very
quick and straight forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this time it was 9pm and very dark. We&#39;d always planned to camp the other
side of the border as Novosibirsk was quite a drive away, and we&#39;d had to leave
Kazakhstan as you have to register after five days and we were on our fifth
day. So we drove a little way into Russia, turned into a side road, drove
enough of a distance to be hidden from the road (so we thought) setup camp and
had noodles with egg for dinner. Again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were awoken by the sound of a vehicle. It was definitely coming towards us.
I knew it was going to stop at our tent. It stopped at our tent. There was a
shout. Probably in Russian. I reluctantly unzipped the door. There were three
Russian soldiers with guns standing around their Lada 4x4. Kai got up and I
started to pack away our things. We didn&#39;t share much in the way of language,
but once they&#39;d seen our passports they left. We weren&#39;t sure if they wanted us
to leave or not, but three guys with guns worked pretty well as an alarm clock
and it was past 7am so we decided to leave, without even the cup of tea we&#39;d
offered the soldiers.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Kazakhstan_Into_Russia/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Kazakhstan_Into_Russia/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Astana</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Astana/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Astana/"/>






	<category term="Kazakhstan" />

	<category term="jamie" />


	<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
	<published>2011-08-31T05:22:30Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;The drive to Astana was very long but fairly uneventful. If you have a look at
&lt;a href=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/map/&quot;&gt;the map&lt;/a&gt; you can see we drove around a very large lake in the south of the
country, which was an absolutely &lt;a href=&quot;https://maps.google.com/?ll=45.759859,76.168213&amp;amp;spn=4.522295,9.854736&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;z=7&amp;amp;vpsrc=6&quot;&gt;beautiful perfect turquoise colour&lt;/a&gt;, not unlike
the Kazakh flag, maybe that&#39;s where it comes from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Darkness fell between 7 and 8 when we still had a considerable distance to go.
By that point we&#39;d driven for about 12 hours and covered about 3/4 of the
1100km (passing our 10,000th mile on the way). Passing through Karagandy there
were a couple of signed detours along surprisingly bad roads, considering that
we were travelling from Kazakhstan&#39;s biggest city to its capital. At one point
I was following a couple of cars along a flyover when they drove around a small
road block. I followed, not thinking much of it. Then we came to another road
block and both cars turned off the road. I followed. The road got smaller and
smaller until it was barely a dusty track. We crossed several railway tracks.
Kai started to freak out. Just as I was beginning to wonder if we should turn
around we found tarmac again, and eventually met the main road again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incredible. Relief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reaching Astana at midnight we managed to find a hotel very quickly, and went
straight to bed. We&#39;d been driving for 16 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stories of Astana we&#39;d heard in Almaty led me to imagine something along
the lines of Ashgabat, lots of new but empty and useless/already fading
buildings. But actually it was pretty normal as things go. Kai and I went to
see the Norman Foster &quot;tent&quot; this morning. It looked disappointedly small from
the outside, but it does manage to contain a six story shopping mall. As a
measure of how bright it is here, I took a picture &lt;em&gt;inside&lt;/em&gt; the shopping mall
at ISO 100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re now rushin&#39; to Russia. We&#39;ll probably camp tonight, hopefully inside
Russia, and make Novosibirsk tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/6107553957/&quot; title=&quot;Norman Foster&#39;s Astana Tent by Jamie Kitson, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6196/6107553957_fd6d88a8db.jpg&quot; width=&quot;331&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;Norman Foster&#39;s Astana Tent&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Astana/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Astana/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Kyrgyzstan</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Kyrgyzstan/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Kyrgyzstan/"/>






	<category term="Kyrgyzstan" />

	<category term="jamie" />

	<category term="kai" />


	<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
	<published>2011-08-27T08:57:53Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;So after waking up in the yurt after an uncomfortable night&#39;s sleep we packed
up early for a dash to Murghab where we should have been that morning and onto
the border.  We met An American &lt;a href=&quot;https://brucealmaty.wordpress.com/author/brucealmaty/&quot;&gt;Team Bruce
Almaty&lt;/a&gt; and a South
African solo team named Guy there, which was nice. We also took on an Israeli
hitchhiker called Dal who was desperate to get to Bishkek by the 26th for a
flight to India, which was the matched our itinerary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/6088376870/&quot; title=&quot;DSC_9992 by Jamie Kitson, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6086/6088376870_32e9d1bc1e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;331&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_9992&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were a bit nervous as we heard a couple of reports of challenging roads once
we set off. We went through one after another fearing that was worse to come,
and we were all surprised when we unexpectedly hit the border. The border was
just a shack where it looked like a checkpoint that we&#39;ve seen time and time
again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We struggled to pay the least possible bribe and eventually settled on $10 for both teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point we had a flat and another tyre had a bulge in the side the size
of a golf ball, so we did the Pamirs with some scars to prove it. As usual we
completed a major leg of the journey and it was an anti-climax. It is difficult
to celebrate when you&#39;re exhausted and there is no champagne. &lt;img src=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/smileys/smile4.png&quot; alt=&quot;;)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pushed onto Osh and after some insane night driving where there was far too
many animals and other dangers on the road. We checked into a LP recommendation
Hotel Altai and it was absolutely abysmal. Nothing worked, not even in the taps
in the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we wanted to deal with the two tyres before setting off on the
10hr drive to Bishkek. We found the &quot;Car (Machina) Bizaare&quot; with the help of
Team Bruce Almaty and we hoped we could get everything sorted in a bit more
than an hour, in order to leave by midday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two hours later, blood, sweat, tears and ~30USD lighter we managed to get both
done. What was silly was that the power for the block was out, so I to search
out a place with a generator. It also didn&#39;t help the first second hand tyre we
were sold had a massive hole in it. The next one was the wrong size, slightly
bigger. We didn&#39;t notice until we drove off with it.  So now when we hit a bump
on the back right side, we can hear it hitting the wheel arch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless we moved on with Dal still in the back. It soon transpired we could
not close on Bishkek, though we managed to find a pleasant hotel in Totagul on
the way. Early next morning we aimed for Almaty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Jamie&#39;s Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/6084575879/&quot; title=&quot;Jamie fixes a puncture by Kai Hendry, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6208/6084575879_f030d7198d_t.jpg&quot; width=&quot;75&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; alt=&quot;Jamie fixes a puncture&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;After spending most of the night weeing out of my bottom in the absolutely disgusting, 
but thankfully en suite and functional (unlike the &quot;shower&quot; or basin)
toilet of our room at Hotel Altai (I
must appologise to the four other people sharing the room) I wasn&#39;t exactly feeling
great. As I didn&#39;t think stopping every five mintutes for a toilet break was really
an option I decided to take something to stop the diarrhea, and then we went out
for a hearty breakfast, one of the heariest breakfasts we&#39;ve had. Taking Imodium and then
eating a large meal is not something that I recommend. As we looked around the tyre market
in the heat and checked out a few prospective tyres
I felt sicker and sicker. Really like the food in my stomach had nowhere to go. I just
prayed that it wouldn&#39;t go upwards. Kai took the bulging tyre off to be changed and left
me with the car. I got the punctured spare out and started the process of fixing it
using the Crafty Plugger kit I&#39;d brought from London, battling with a kid from one of
the tyre places who thought, wrongly, that he knew how to use it better than I did. The 
sun beat down. I got a bowl out of the car and prepared for the worse. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two days later and I have finally recovered. I swear I will never drink that fizzy yak&#39;s
milk again. Though having said that no one else was fool enough to drink it, and they
all came down with the same symptoms, at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Kyrgyzstan/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Kyrgyzstan/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>
<entry>
	<title>The Mongol Rally is actually a bit of a jolly</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/The_Mongol_Rally_is_actually_a_bit_of_a_jolly/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/The_Mongol_Rally_is_actually_a_bit_of_a_jolly/"/>






	<category term="Uzbekistan" />

	<category term="jamie" />


	<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
	<published>2011-08-20T18:03:15Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;We had a really good day today, despite some really depressing news last night.
As Kai wrote, yesterday we crossed into Uzbekistan, which was probably one of
the least pleasant border crossings yet, but still the hardest bit is remaining
patient. However last night I happened to check my emails, the first time in a
while as internet was really hard to come by in Turmenistan, and Team America
had emailed warning that the Uzbek border guards had been wondering where we
were as we had &quot;missed a step&quot;, and needed to go back to get our &quot;yellow form&quot;.
As we&#39;d left I did wonder how come we still had both copies of our customs
declaration forms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we made the decision this morning to go back. I was in more of a mind to
risk it, but Kai has become risk-averse of late. Good thing too. It was also
lucky that we hadn&#39;t gone all the way to Samarqant as I had suggested as there
would have been no way we would have wanted to drive back the 700 odd km to the
border. (To be honest Buxoro was nicer to visit than Samarqant anyway.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after a few last trips to the toilet in our water-less hostel, we left at
about 8:30am and made good progress, getting back to the border at about
9:30am. In contrast to the day before the border was very quiet and we got back
to the customs office easily. There the two male and female guards recognised
us, pretended to be cross with us, told us that we must thank the friends who
notified us as we would now be able to leave the country, and sent us on our
way. The guards outside were a bit annoyed when I played with their attack dog,
it was so cute, but still didn&#39;t have any water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then made quick time back to Buxoro for a very good lunch (I opted for beef
shashlik again, as it was so good last night. Kai&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pilaf&quot;&gt;plov&lt;/a&gt; was very good too,
which I was surprised at) stopping only to see if we could get some fuel from
one of the very few open petrol stations which all have very long queues
outside. I walked down to check that they had 95 octane &quot;benzene&quot; and we were
waved in, past all the locals (sorry locals).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made it to Samarqand for about 6, stopping once so that Kai could take a dip
in a very grey/brown fast flowing river, which we had a job getting him out of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully tomorrow we will make it to and through the Tajik border, stay the
night and start the Pamir Highway on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we started this trip I was a bit concerned as Kai was always talking
about two months, while my work had given me 6-7 weeks. Once we started however
it was me who was suggesting we spend a bit more time in, for instance, Iran,
and Kai was then getting nervous about being left behind by the rest of the
ralliers. When we left Iran I was quite happy with our progress as we&#39;d done
about 6500 miles in three and a bit weeks and only had about 2000 left to go.
However, one day into Turkmenistan, driving to Mary, and I realised how a bad
road can turn your 800km days into 200km days and so many small countries means
the border crossings start to eat up time and I began to get nervous. Since
Mary the roads have been much better, hopefully they  won&#39;t get too bad, else I
might have to leave Kai to finish the rally on his own &lt;img src=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/smileys/smile4.png&quot; alt=&quot;;)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/The_Mongol_Rally_is_actually_a_bit_of_a_jolly/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/The_Mongol_Rally_is_actually_a_bit_of_a_jolly/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Hell Mouth&#44; Turkmenistan</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Hell_Mouth__44___Turkmenistan/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Hell_Mouth__44___Turkmenistan/"/>






	<category term="Turkmenistan" />

	<category term="jamie" />


	<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
	<published>2011-08-19T18:35:51Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/6177495903/&quot; title=&quot;IMG_0460 by Kai Hendry, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6151/6177495903_0823d39205.jpg&quot; width=&quot;374&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_0460&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 40 years ago, 300 odd kilometers north of Ashgabat in Turkmenistan some
noxtious gases were seeping out of the ground at a drilling site. It was
decided to burn off the gases and so they were lit. The ground collapsed, the
rig fell into the hole, and the fire has been burning ever since. It&#39;s quite a
sight, and tourists have been going to have a look ever since. Now apparently
the Turkmen authorities don&#39;t like tourists, and I imagine the whole episode
was a bit of an embarrassment, so they took the logical step and raised the
local village, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Derweze&quot;&gt;Darvaza&lt;/a&gt;, to the ground
(leaving the bread oven standing due to religious reverance) to desaude
visitors. It is against this backdrop that Kai and I left Ashgabat yesterday
afternoon and headed north.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driving 300km through desert is a thirsty business and by the time we got to
what I assume had once been Darvaza, complete with lone bread oven and a handy
wall to hide the car behind, we&#39;d already drunk about half of the water we had
with us. We also hadn&#39;t seen a petrol station since just outside Ashgabat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before Darvaza, suspiciously close infact, had been a police check point.
This panicked us a bit, hence the hiding of the car, and we decided to wait
until dark and then walk the last three miles through the desert to the &quot;hell
mouth&quot;.  Not quite as crazy as it sounds as Kai had already put the coordinates
into his GPS device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking through the desert was a little spooky. Kai claims he saw a snake, but
it could have just been a moving stick &lt;img src=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/smileys/smile4.png&quot; alt=&quot;;)&quot; /&gt; Gradually in the distance we started
to see a slight glow on the horizon, and after climbing yet anouther ridge we
saw...  the moon. But all was not lost, there was definitely something else
glowing out there. After a total of about an hour and a half we did eventually
reach the great fire pit. It was nice, very peaceful and we scaled an
overlooking hill and sat for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it was nice to see, and walking through the desert was an experience, I&#39;m
not sure I&#39;d recommend it, or at least not the way that we did it. There is
apparently a track that leads to it if you can find it, or you can try to find
a guide, and you can camp nearby. As we returned and were getting close to the
car we heard a motorbike behind us, which by the time we got to the car had
caught up with is, and at just the same, as if on schedule, two other
motorbikes drew up, from opposite directions. The riders seemed to want to take
us on a tour of the flame pit. We tried to explain that we&#39;d already been. They
stayed and chatted and gave us some chewing tobbacco, which was a bit strong,
and asked for gifts. Luckily we had some cigarettes and a pen and they left
eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Hell_Mouth__44___Turkmenistan/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Hell_Mouth__44___Turkmenistan/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>
<entry>
	<title>The Iranian Border</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/The_Iranian_Border/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/The_Iranian_Border/"/>






	<category term="borders" />

	<category term="iran" />

	<category term="jamie" />


	<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
	<published>2011-08-09T18:38:10Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;As that Queen song goes, it started off so well. We had made it out of Turkey
without paying anyone to carry our documents from our car 10 meters to the
check point, it was calm and relaxed and we hadn&#39;t seen any beards or even
guns. We&#39;d had to be a bit patient while they checked our passports, and then
took our finger prints. Kai&#39;s for the second time as he&#39;d already given them at
the Consulate in the UK, I&#39;d thought I&#39;d gotten away with it after their
machine broke, at the border we were back to old fashioned, reliable ink and
paper. We then gave them the carnet, our car&#39;s passport, and waited some more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We chatted with the officials, they seemed very interested in us, we showed
them our Persian guide book on my Kindle (I&#39;d previously removed Salmon Rushdie
and made sure not to show them that it could still access Twitter and
Facebook), they loved my tattoos, if laughing and pointing can be described as
&quot;loved&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One guard in particular became quite interested in our car, pointing at stuff
and asking what it was. The first thing that sparked his interest was Kai&#39;s
Gerber multitool. He pointed at it and said &quot;Gift?&quot; I explained that it wasn&#39;t
mine. He then went to the back of the car and asked what the long red and blue
bags were. I explained that they were chairs (£5 from ASDA), and he got one
out, and sat on it, asking if it was made in England.  He called Kai over and
repeated the multitool-gift trick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kai searched for anything else that he might be happy with, trying to fob him
off with some &quot;expensive&quot; Cafe Direct tea, the guard asked if it was made in
England. Eventually Kai gave him one of his Geekout &quot;KitKai&quot; T-shirts, and he
was very happy, asking again if it was made in England. A little while later
our documents were ready, and we were asked for 20 Euros. This made me quite
cross. I thought we probably could have driven off, but Kai didn&#39;t want to piss
them off so I offered them 10, which was accepted. We were directed to customs,
which we missed and were turned back from the exit gates. We went to a small
green cabin, where we were given another slip of paper. We went to a manic
building with one small kiosk window and absolutely no form of queuing system
and worried that our documents had been lost somewhere.  We went back to the
green cabin and were asked how much we&#39;d paid at the border. I was honest and
we were asked for another 10 Euros. We handed over 10 Turkish Lira, about 5
Euros and were finally allowed to leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/6026638952/&quot; title=&quot;Iranian Border by Jamie Kitson, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6193/6026638952_483075b09b_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;424&quot; alt=&quot;Iranian Border&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/The_Iranian_Border/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/The_Iranian_Border/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>

</feed>
