<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged carnet</title>
<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/tags/carnet/"/>
<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/tags/carnet/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Team Geekout (Jamie&Kai) geeked out on the Mongol Rally 2011</name>

</author>




<id>https://geekout.org.uk/tags/carnet/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Team Geekout (Jamie&amp;Kai) geeked out on the Mongol Rally 2011</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2011-06-24T15:14:31Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>Of Visas and Carnets</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Of_Visas_and_Carnets/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Of_Visas_and_Carnets/"/>






	<category term="car" />

	<category term="carnet" />

	<category term="iran" />

	<category term="jamie" />

	<category term="visas" />


	<updated>2011-06-24T15:14:31Z</updated>
	<published>2011-06-24T10:26:56Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve been getting lots of (well, two) scary emails from the Adventurists regarding all the official, bureaucratic stuff that we need to get done before the start of the Rally, exactly 29 days away now, especially the Carnet de Passage. The Carnet is basically a passport for the car, which we need in order to get through Iran, and to be able to leave the Micra in Mongolia. I sent the form off a couple of days ago along with a colour copy of the details pages of my passport and the V5. Yesterday I realised that I had not ticketed one of the boxes, and after all the dire warnings from the Adventurists and the RAC (for example, if the colour of the upholstery changes, or the make of the radio, you have to get a new Carnet) and the cost of the damn thing I rang the RAC in a panic expecting some boring official to tell me in a nasal voice that I would have to do the whole thing again. But no, to my surprise a very nice, helpful and relaxed guy answered and told me they&#39;d received my application that morning and not to worry, everything was fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news the Iranian embassy cancelled my first visa appointment. We have used the Adventurists&#39; visa service (the &quot;Visa Machine&quot;) to get our visas, which seems to be going well, despite initial hiccups with the website (it kept forgetting our dates) and confusion over what we actually had to do (I assumed, wrongly, that they would even fill in the forms for us, it didn&#39;t seem that clear what we had to do once we&#39;d finished the website bit). My rearranged appointment is now on Wednesday, which will apparently be quicker than the more popular Sunday at 9am slot, which I didn&#39;t fancy much anyway. I think the reason we need to be there is to get our finger prints taken, something the Adventurists really couldn&#39;t have done for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jamie&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Of_Visas_and_Carnets/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Of_Visas_and_Carnets/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>

</feed>
