<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged Istanbul</title>
<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/tags/Istanbul/"/>
<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/tags/Istanbul/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Team Geekout (Jamie&Kai) geeked out on the Mongol Rally 2011</name>

</author>




<id>https://geekout.org.uk/tags/Istanbul/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Team Geekout (Jamie&amp;Kai) geeked out on the Mongol Rally 2011</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>Bulgaria to Turkey</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Bulgaria_to_Turkey/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Bulgaria_to_Turkey/"/>






	<category term="Istanbul" />

	<category term="bulgaria" />

	<category term="kai" />

	<category term="turkey" />


	<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
	<published>2011-08-04T16:10:07Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;349&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/U0sJxuT2txQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bulgaria was surprisingly OK. For me it&#39;s a strange mix of Russian (they
understand it, unlike the Romanians seemingly) and France (cute rustic
buildings and amazing countryside). Food is pretty bad and I&#39;m totally
unconvinced on Bulgarian&#39;s sense of taste and style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Varna and resorts to the south seemed popular for the English tourists and to
be honest the prices and women are quite attractive. Ahem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we quickly did the UNESCO tourist trap of Nessebar and headed into Turkey.
Border crossing was great... friendly staff and an initial hiccup with their
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/kaihendry/status/98788319923666944&quot;&gt;computer failing&lt;/a&gt;.
What a super drive. The scenery was stunning and dropping into Turkey was like
entering another world. Fantastic scenery.  Awesome sunset. Incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turkish roads and infrastructure seem amazingly good. We were a little worried
we forgot the &lt;a
href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vignette_(road_tax)&quot;&gt;Vignette&lt;/a&gt;, though we
picked up a KSG Auto-bahn card at a petrol station. We were easily averaging
100km/h and we made it into Istanbul with the help of Google maps... without
incident. Nuts. [Good driving, huh? - Jamie]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 50EUR per night twin room hostel in Istanbul&#39;s Sultanahmet is a bit poor
value for money to say the least.  There seems to be a chasm between &quot;hostel&quot;
and &quot;hotel&quot; and it&#39;s really hard to bridge it. I am not interested really in
talking with tourists from UK and the West [unless they&#39;re good looking]. I&#39;m
more keen to chat with locals.  A decent wifi Internet connection would be nice
too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/6008557642/&quot; title=&quot;In Istanbul, not Constantinople&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6004/6008557642_9a60a54644_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;424&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today the weather is pretty hot, though I&#39;ve got the Blue Mosque, the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/6007851939/&quot;&gt;bath&lt;/a&gt; and the Sofia Mosque
out the way and I&#39;m feeling pretty weak and dazed. There is a lot of history
here which makes me feel a little depressed tbh. Life is incredibly short in
the scheme of things and I worry a bit how I fit in...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frustratingly Google Maps does not work (very strange) and we don&#39;t have a map
of Iran*. Can&#39;t help but feel our lack of planning ahead is catching up with us.
And finding information with a shit internet connection in Istanbul is crazy
hard compared to London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Must thank Ruth who I contacted to help find some accommodation in Turkey for
us. I did another &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/kaihendry/status/99104332758265857&quot;&gt;shout
out&lt;/a&gt; for help
tomorrow, wonder if anyone gets it (Folks did!!
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/TurkeyTourismUK/status/99108049226186755&quot;&gt;Thank&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/ED8617/status/99145705771376640&quot;&gt;you&lt;/a&gt; ). I guess we
should just chance it, but it could easily cost us a lot of time. I&#39;m keen to
spend 2-3 days in Tehran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve had the epiphany that Istanbul is well... the centre of the world. They
way it bridges continents and the understated Black and Aegean sea. It&#39;s just
insanely strategic. I want Turkey in the EU. &lt;img src=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* Jamie: After going to multiple bookshops and drawing a complete blank on
Iranian maps I was advised by a tourist agency to try the Iranian Consulate. I
pictured an office block, but arriving I found a gated community. Nervous I
asked the Turkish policeman on guard whether it was alright to bother them, he
said yes and upon entering I found a small man, who understood enough English
to give me a map of attractions. It doesn&#39;t have any roads on it but it&#39;s
better than nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Bulgaria_to_Turkey/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Bulgaria_to_Turkey/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>

</feed>
