<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged passport</title>
<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/tags/passport/"/>
<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/tags/passport/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Team Geekout (Jamie&Kai) geeked out on the Mongol Rally 2011</name>

</author>




<id>https://geekout.org.uk/tags/passport/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Team Geekout (Jamie&amp;Kai) geeked out on the Mongol Rally 2011</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2019-09-03T15:05:28Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>One Week and Counting</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/One_Week_and_Counting/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/One_Week_and_Counting/"/>






	<category term="car" />

	<category term="iran" />

	<category term="jamie" />

	<category term="passport" />

	<category term="visas" />


	<updated>2019-09-03T15:05:28Z</updated>
	<published>2019-08-31T06:46:10Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;a href=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Not_the_Best_Day_of_My_Life/&quot;&gt;I last wrote&lt;/a&gt; much has happened, but not much seems to have changed. I got a new passport, at great expense. My old passport, containing four of my seven required visas has had a very large corner cut off the data page, meaning there&#39;s no way I&#39;ll be able to fool border guards into thinking that it&#39;s valid. I&#39;ve been told I don&#39;t need to return to the Iranian Embassy, Masha&#39;Allah, as their finger print machine is broken. I&#39;ve been told various things about the validity of the four visas in my old passport, ranging from the Kyrgyzstan Embassy telling me that I needed to get a completely new visa, through the Adventurists telling me that the Kyrgyzstan border guards are very relaxed to a very chilled Uzbek Embassy worker telling me that everything would be fine. I&#39;ve had to pay for my Russian and Mongolian visas to be expedited. The amount of money this is costing is getting ridiculous. Apparently there is much nervousness over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/219322734774041&quot;&gt;the Facebook group&lt;/a&gt; as no one seems to have their Russian, Iranian or Mongolian visas, according to the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/5937712559/&quot; title=&quot;Josh Cutting Our Sump Guard by Jamie Kitson, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6142/5937712559_e0920110d3_t.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;66&quot; alt=&quot;Josh Cutting Our Sump Guard&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/5938270040/&quot; title=&quot;Finished! by Jamie Kitson, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6140/5938270040_7246a87656_t.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;66&quot; alt=&quot;Finished!&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;I spent a very successful Sunday with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/5821344968/&quot;&gt;Josh Hall&lt;/a&gt; who put together a sump guard for our Micra very speedily and professionally. I took a photo of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/5938270174/in/photostream&quot;&gt;the template&lt;/a&gt; in case it would be useful to anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parcel upon parcel has been arriving at my parents&#39; house, mostly technology that Kai has ordered, I am wondering whether we will be able to fit it all in the car. I got a distinctly old fashioned &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.navitron.org.uk/forum/index.php?action=dlattach%3Btopic=4308.0%3Battach=1572%3Bimage&quot;&gt;Kelly Kettle&lt;/a&gt; for my birthday from Mum, which at least we don&#39;t need another cigarette lighter adapter for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came back to my parent&#39;s this weekend hoping to do a last shop for tools and spares, but unfortunately Pete at Steyning Motor Spares hasn&#39;t had his delivery yet and doesn&#39;t know what he will/won&#39;t have. And Hove Motor Spares still doesn&#39;t have an extra spare for us. Being a teacher my mum is on holiday from Tuesday, so I might be calling on her time somewhat as I am working right up until we leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/5937712197/&quot; title=&quot;KitKai by Jamie Kitson, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6131/5937712197_1b25a2421d_t.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;66&quot; alt=&quot;KitKai&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;My house mate Larry&#39;s made us some wonderful T-shirts, KitKai, geddit?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jamie&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/One_Week_and_Counting/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/One_Week_and_Counting/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>

</feed>
