<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>pages tagged Kyrgyzstan</title>
<link>https://geekout.org.uk/tags/Kyrgyzstan/</link>
<atom:link href="https://geekout.org.uk/tags/Kyrgyzstan/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<description>Team Geekout (Jamie&amp;Kai) geeked out on the Mongol Rally 2011</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 16:07:02 +0100</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>Kyrgyzstan</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Kyrgyzstan/</guid>

	<link>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Kyrgyzstan/</link>



	<category>Kyrgyzstan</category>

	<category>jamie</category>

	<category>kai</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 09:57:53 +0100</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;So after waking up in the yurt after an uncomfortable night&#39;s sleep we packed
up early for a dash to Murghab where we should have been that morning and onto
the border.  We met An American &lt;a href=&quot;https://brucealmaty.wordpress.com/author/brucealmaty/&quot;&gt;Team Bruce
Almaty&lt;/a&gt; and a South
African solo team named Guy there, which was nice. We also took on an Israeli
hitchhiker called Dal who was desperate to get to Bishkek by the 26th for a
flight to India, which was the matched our itinerary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/6088376870/&quot; title=&quot;DSC_9992 by Jamie Kitson, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6086/6088376870_32e9d1bc1e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;331&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_9992&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were a bit nervous as we heard a couple of reports of challenging roads once
we set off. We went through one after another fearing that was worse to come,
and we were all surprised when we unexpectedly hit the border. The border was
just a shack where it looked like a checkpoint that we&#39;ve seen time and time
again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We struggled to pay the least possible bribe and eventually settled on $10 for both teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point we had a flat and another tyre had a bulge in the side the size
of a golf ball, so we did the Pamirs with some scars to prove it. As usual we
completed a major leg of the journey and it was an anti-climax. It is difficult
to celebrate when you&#39;re exhausted and there is no champagne. &lt;img src=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/smileys/smile4.png&quot; alt=&quot;;)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pushed onto Osh and after some insane night driving where there was far too
many animals and other dangers on the road. We checked into a LP recommendation
Hotel Altai and it was absolutely abysmal. Nothing worked, not even in the taps
in the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we wanted to deal with the two tyres before setting off on the
10hr drive to Bishkek. We found the &quot;Car (Machina) Bizaare&quot; with the help of
Team Bruce Almaty and we hoped we could get everything sorted in a bit more
than an hour, in order to leave by midday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two hours later, blood, sweat, tears and ~30USD lighter we managed to get both
done. What was silly was that the power for the block was out, so I to search
out a place with a generator. It also didn&#39;t help the first second hand tyre we
were sold had a massive hole in it. The next one was the wrong size, slightly
bigger. We didn&#39;t notice until we drove off with it.  So now when we hit a bump
on the back right side, we can hear it hitting the wheel arch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless we moved on with Dal still in the back. It soon transpired we could
not close on Bishkek, though we managed to find a pleasant hotel in Totagul on
the way. Early next morning we aimed for Almaty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Jamie&#39;s Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/6084575879/&quot; title=&quot;Jamie fixes a puncture by Kai Hendry, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6208/6084575879_f030d7198d_t.jpg&quot; width=&quot;75&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; alt=&quot;Jamie fixes a puncture&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;After spending most of the night weeing out of my bottom in the absolutely disgusting, 
but thankfully en suite and functional (unlike the &quot;shower&quot; or basin)
toilet of our room at Hotel Altai (I
must appologise to the four other people sharing the room) I wasn&#39;t exactly feeling
great. As I didn&#39;t think stopping every five mintutes for a toilet break was really
an option I decided to take something to stop the diarrhea, and then we went out
for a hearty breakfast, one of the heariest breakfasts we&#39;ve had. Taking Imodium and then
eating a large meal is not something that I recommend. As we looked around the tyre market
in the heat and checked out a few prospective tyres
I felt sicker and sicker. Really like the food in my stomach had nowhere to go. I just
prayed that it wouldn&#39;t go upwards. Kai took the bulging tyre off to be changed and left
me with the car. I got the punctured spare out and started the process of fixing it
using the Crafty Plugger kit I&#39;d brought from London, battling with a kid from one of
the tyre places who thought, wrongly, that he knew how to use it better than I did. The 
sun beat down. I got a bowl out of the car and prepared for the worse. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two days later and I have finally recovered. I swear I will never drink that fizzy yak&#39;s
milk again. Though having said that no one else was fool enough to drink it, and they
all came down with the same symptoms, at some point.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


	<comments>/posts/Kyrgyzstan/#comments</comments>

</item>

</channel>
</rss>
