<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>blog</title>
<link>https://geekout.org.uk/blog/</link>
<atom:link href="https://geekout.org.uk/blog/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<description>Team Geekout (Jamie&amp;Kai) geeked out on the Mongol Rally 2011</description>
<generator>ikiwiki</generator>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 10:09:00 +0100</pubDate>
<item>
	<title>A Message To Our Sponsors</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geekout.org.uk/posts/A_Message_To_Our_Sponsors/</guid>

	<link>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/A_Message_To_Our_Sponsors/</link>



	<category>jamie</category>

	<category>sponsorship</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 07:46:10 +0100</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-09-12T09:09:00Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;letter&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hello!
&lt;p&gt;
First of all thank you very much for your sponsorship, it was much
appreciated by Kai and I as it allowed us to get off on our little
jaunt, and I&#39;m sure it will be appreciated almost as much by our two
charities, Amnesty International and the Christina Noble Children&#39;s
Foundation in Mongolia. The current total is £1570, though since we&#39;ve
finished we&#39;ve had a small flurry of donations.
&lt;p&gt;
Now on to what you have all been waiting for, the results! We arrived
at the finish line at approximately 4:57pm Mongolia time on Thursday
8th September, which I make 6 weeks, 4 days, 18 hours and 57 minutes,
having done 12,566 miles, or 20,223 km.
&lt;p&gt;
In the distance guess Rachel gets a special mention, as the only
person to overestimate, however we didn&#39;t quite hit the 30,000 mile
mark I&#39;m afraid Rachel. Claudio&#39;s guess of 8425 miles was just pipped
by Sara and Rob&#39;s guess of 8454.4 miles. As Claudio said, we certainly
did more miles than planned.
&lt;p&gt;
In the time guess Larry and Gez both predicted 4th September, just
four days off, but my sister Maddy (Sara and Rob&#39;s niece, keeping it
in the family) managed a guess just 16 hours out!
&lt;p&gt;
Prizes will be distributed to those two lucky, or skilled, winners,
but if the rest of you would like to send me your address I will post
you a (very small) token of our appreciation.
&lt;p&gt;
The rally itself went pretty well for us, if you haven&#39;t been keeping
up our blog is at https://geekout.org.uk/ and a map of our trip is
here: https://geekout.org.uk/map/
&lt;p&gt;
Back to work for me tomorrow.
&lt;p&gt;
Thanks again, Jamie
&lt;/div&gt;
If you&#39;ve enjoyed our updates, and haven&#39;t already, maybe it&#39;s time to think about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justgiving.com/teams/geekout/&quot;&gt;donating&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


	<comments>/posts/A_Message_To_Our_Sponsors/#comments</comments>

</item>
<item>
	<title>Altai Mongolia</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Altai_Mongolia/</guid>

	<link>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Altai_Mongolia/</link>



	<category>kai</category>

	<category>mongolia</category>

	<category>russia</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 07:46:10 +0100</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-09-03T03:49:00Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;We set off for the Altai Mountains from Novosibirsk by keeping to the rather good M52 road. We
knew we were in the Altai when we started seeing these quite beautiful
mountains and accompanying rivers. There were many guest houses and some camp
spots on the way, though none seemed suitable to us. Too close to a house. Too
close to a road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As dusk fell we found ourselves in a very wet misty area of the Altai where the
road struck off from the main river. After some abortive searching we found a suitable
place, though the road was too muddy to take our Micra to our camp site. We
ended up parking the car by the road and carrying our stuff to the sodden camping
ground near a worryingly high stream. We setup just before a downpour. In the rain we cooked
Ramen and we ate it in the tent. Thunder and lightning made it a bit of a
dreary/exciting night, nonetheless I am kind of glad to have the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/6108106092/&quot; title=&quot;Breakfast Picnic and Drying by Jamie Kitson, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6086/6108106092_26c180ebf6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;331&quot; alt=&quot;Breakfast Picnic and Drying&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we were back on the M52 heading for Tashanta. After a couple of hours the damp mist lifted and a
warming sun came out. We stopped and  made eggs with
smoked wieners on the bank of a scenic [apart from all the rubish :(] river where we found out that we had been
featured in an online Nsk newspaper, being the most popular article (15,000 hits!) and even acquired a female fan! 
We laid out all our wet camping gear, which dried very quickly in the morning sun. The news, the drying and the 
breakfast all lifted our previously damp [haha] spirits and we hit the road, very keen to get into Mongolia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhat surprisingly the landscape very quickly changed from green mountainsides to light
brown sandy slopes. It looked like Mongolia all of a sudden. Usual border
crossing shenanigans entailed, including our first really thorough search upon leaving Russia,
though I felt like a veteran at this stage and I was almost sad that it was our last one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was off that the Russian immigration officer wanted 100 rubles in some
registration fee. What cheek. It was worse on the Mongolian side. A 5USD
disinfectant fee? Passport control offering to change money? Various fees from
7 to 10 dollars for god knows what. Anyhoo, we got through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a list of all the Mongol ralliers and it was interesting to see that
yes, indeed, we were one of the very last to cross.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/6108116726/&quot; title=&quot;Mongolia by Jamie Kitson, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6205/6108116726_f3e64dd9c3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;331&quot; alt=&quot;Mongolia&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We met 2 Norwegians in a fire truck which was good. Then on the road we met the
four motorcyclists/mopedists we&#39;d met in Turkey, who&#39;d already stopped to camp. They were in good spirits and I must say
they must have had quite a strenuous rally! From the insurance office on the border
we&#39;d picked up a female hitch hiker, who later sang in our car, which provided
us some entertainment on the way to Olgii.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were keen to get to Olgii as Team America had been in touch with us, they
must have realised we were only a day behind and were looking for someone to
travel with to UB. We were too tbh, so I was glad to see their invite. We are
about to breakfast with them and they are keen to go off the beaten track and
take the more challenging &quot;Northern route&quot;. As opposed to the &quot;Southern route&quot; which the
Mongol Rally handbook seems to only mention. Tbh I am keen to do the track
other ralliers do, but then again I am brimming with confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the handbook says, fast speeds and big rocks end badly. It also mentions if
everything goes well, you should make UB in 5 days. Jamie now has 6.5 days until his
flight, so this going to be tight.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


	<comments>/posts/Altai_Mongolia/#comments</comments>

</item>
<item>
	<title>Altay to Bayankhongor&#44; Mongolia</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Altay_to_Bayankhongor__44___Mongolia/</guid>

	<link>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Altay_to_Bayankhongor__44___Mongolia/</link>



	<category>jamie</category>

	<category>mongolia</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 07:46:10 +0100</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-09-07T04:19:42Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;We travelled for most of the day in convoy with the five other teams, having
fun with the driving, sliding around and racing each other. Micras are
definitely well suited to Mongolian roads, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mud-lab.com&quot;&gt;Mud Lab&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s 1.6L
Peugeot 306 the only one able to keep up with the two Micras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch Kai and I and Mud Lab broke away from the four other teams and made
it into Altay, Mud Lab running low on both fuel and money. We milled around in the town for a bit, picking up some supplies
&amp;amp; money, Mud Lab making some more repairs. This time, worryingly, to their
brakes, having already had to fix a fuel leak on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided I was tired of noodles and fancied eating in a restaurant. A helpful
gentleman said, through a translator on the phone, that he would show us a place.
He got in our car and we literally drove around the block. He showed us a restaurant.
The guy on the phone then said we should give him 15,000 of the local currency.
Reluctantly I did. He refused asking for 20,000. By this time Kai was still sitting
in the drivers seat, but I was out of the car and the guy was blocking my way.
Eventually Kai started to drive off, I jumped in the front seat and we sped off back
to Mud Lab. Considering that it was just around the corner we were concerned that
we might have an angry Mongolian or two on our tail and were rather put off Altay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kai and I decided to go ahead and scout out potential camp sites, but when we found
how cold and windy it was went back into town to have a look at hotels. We weren&#39;t
impressed and together with Mud Lab and their newly working brakes headed out. We
aimed for what we thought could be a natural wind break over a hill, but managed to
end up in a natural wind tunnel. It started to rain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day was slow going, partially due to the bad roads, but mostly due to
Mud Lab&#39;s bad luck. (Or perhaps poor planing in choosing a Peugeot  ;).) After a
couple of hours driving they sailed over a ridge and hit the other side, blew
both airbags, dislodging their front grill and fan. As they couldn&#39;t reattach
the fan their car started to overheat at regular intervals and they would have
to stop and point their car straight into the wind for a while. Moments after
one of these stops they discovered one of their tyres had split.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards evening the wind was really getting up, causing something like a dust
storm, as we approached a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yurt&quot;&gt;gher&lt;/a&gt; camp and &lt;a
href=&quot;https://maps.google.co.uk/?ll=45.833584,99.372368&amp;amp;spn=0.072121,0.181789&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;z=13&amp;amp;vpsrc=6&quot;&gt;large
river&lt;/a&gt;. Looking at our maps it seemed that the road was on the other side of
the river. Several locals pointed us in the direction of the river and one
offered to tow us across in his tractor for $30 each. We were dubious and
waited. After a while a mini bus approached and we followed it, watching as it
crossed the river, from one island to another. We followed in its footsteps. It
was pretty nerve racking to be honest, especially as there were about four
crossings in total, two of which we hadn&#39;t seen the mini bus cross, but we made
it. I really regret not taking a picture of what greeted us, a desolate,
apocalyptic even, vision of dust caught by the sun blowing across several ghers
and virtually nothing else for as far as the eye could see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this time there was only an hour or two of sunlight left, and we&#39;d only done
about 250km of 400km, but we decided to press on. The roads got even worse and
our speed slowed and slowed as night drew in, and the wind got colder. About
40km from Bayankhongor the road started to get quite wet and muddy. About 10km
from town Mud Lab looked like they got stuck in mud. Their car sounded like it
wasn&#39;t quite in gear. Ale reckons they might have a broken Axel. We managed to
tow them out of the worst of the mud they were in, but didn&#39;t think we&#39;d make
it the 10km due to the mud, we were having difficulty getting just ourselves
out of some of it. So we left them there and went to get help. Practically over
the next hill we were able to see the lights of the town and had mobile signal
and were able to call the Adventurists hot line, but by the time we got back to
Mud Lab to give them the good news they&#39;d already managed to get a tow from a
Mongolian mining magnate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kai and I visited several hotels before picking one we liked and were just
checking in when who should turn up but Mud Lab!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was last night. We woke this morning, opened the curtains and thanked our
lucky stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s snowing!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


	<comments>/posts/Altay_to_Bayankhongor__44___Mongolia/#comments</comments>

</item>
<item>
	<title>Arvaikheer</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Arvaikheer/</guid>

	<link>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Arvaikheer/</link>



	<category>Mongolia</category>

	<category>kai</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 07:46:10 +0100</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-09-10T04:28:55Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/6129218995/&quot; title=&quot;Cold in Mongolia by Kai Hendry, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6066/6129218995_e8d6a54a4e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;374&quot; alt=&quot;Cold in Mongolia&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We towed the Peugeot 306 to the drop off point in Bayanhongor and said goodbye
to the Icelanders. &lt;img src=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/smileys/sad.png&quot; alt=&quot;:(&quot; /&gt;  They were going to catch a bus and meet us in UB
(Ulaanbaatar).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Altai to Bayanhongor definitely seemed like the &lt;strong&gt;hardest stretch&lt;/strong&gt; and we saw
5 or 6 cars at the drop off point that also didn&#39;t finish.  We ate our last
packet of Nong Shim Ramen from the 20 pack box I bought back in New Malden and
we got underway by 2pm. I was quite worried we might be pushing our luck as we
had been told that it would take 4-5hrs to get to Arvaikheer. Thankfully the
weather was fine, most of the snow seemed to disappear and we made it in
4.5hrs. This was our last piece of dirt road, since we knew the next leg was
all sealed. How I am going to miss those &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/6129220415/&quot;&gt;Mongolian
roads&lt;/a&gt;, they were really good
fun. Intense concentration was required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we arrived in Arvaikheer with an hour of sunlight left, so we thought we had
plenty of time to evaluate its hotels. The first one was a building site
outside, but was warm and an OK standard, but a bit dear at ~40USD. The next
place didn&#39;t have its heating on and it had a policemen&#39;s party on the floor
below. You could clearly hear the excruciating Karaoke from below. The next
places were shitholes and we were directed by a Mongolian guide to a couple of
other hotels, but we frustratingly couldn&#39;t find them. After an hour I thought
we should go for the very first hotel, only to find the room was now
unavailable.  Tired, cold, hungry and frustrated. Not a good combination. So we
settled on the place with the Karaoke and we told it would finish by 11pm.
Which it did actually, thankfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we tried to find food and we did find a place with a waitress who was about
16 but amazingly could speak English. We ate dinner and breakfast there.
Breakfast is a nerve racking affair in Mongolia. I am in wonder how they will
screw up the eggs. Broken? Stone cold? Anything is possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I almost forgot to mention we went next door to a night club called &quot;New
Leader&quot; in Arvaikheer. It was cold, the sound system sounded like the speakers
were all blown. The music was a bit hardcore and there tables of mostly hard
looking men ordering a beer for each and a large bottle of vodka for the table. No doubt
people were going to get seriously drunk!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway Arvaikheer was our last night on the road and I was miserable, I hope
you can tell by reading this. &lt;img src=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/smileys/smile4.png&quot; alt=&quot;;)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


	<comments>/posts/Arvaikheer/#comments</comments>

</item>
<item>
	<title>Ashgabat</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Ashgabat/</guid>

	<link>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Ashgabat/</link>



	<category>Turkmenistan</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 07:46:10 +0100</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-08-15T18:35:10Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m tired, my contacts hurt, it&#39;s hot and I am eeking out Internet in the Grand
Turkmen lobby surrounded by prostitutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello from Turkmenistan!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a long drive from Tehran yesterday, we stayed in Goochan. The next day we
drove hungry to the border (no restaurants open on Ramazan of course). Luckily
Jamie stopped to cook up some noodles from a side road in the hills. If we
didn&#39;t I probably would have lost my mind later at the crossing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the border we bumped into a team from Iceland called &lt;a href=&quot;https://mud-lab.com/&quot;&gt;https://mud-lab.com/&lt;/a&gt;.
Before we were thinking we must be one of the last teams. On the top of the
Iran side we bumped into &quot;Team Tigers&quot; and &quot;Two random Germans&quot; who have been
stuck waiting for a Turkmen invitation for &lt;strong&gt;days&lt;/strong&gt;. So it was great to feel
that whole &quot;Adventurists Mongol Rally&quot; spirit again after a week in Iran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &quot;Two random Germans&quot; team asked to interview us which we agreed to, and
after an hour or two of processing we met them to give an interview. Little did
we know the Iranian official was waiting for us. He came over to us after a few
minutes to say &quot;come back tomorrow&quot;. My heart sank and I really though we might
be trapped in Iran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t get me wrong, I love Iran and it was a real shame that official decided
to threaten us. Later he did let us cross.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turkmenistan was almost more farcical than the Iran side. A ton of bureaucracy,
expense (we are completely out of US dollars) and we were through.
Unfortunately we had to tell them our route and later we thought this might
have been a mistake, since we might want to do a diversion to Darvaza, to the
&quot;Gates of Hell&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming down from the mountainous border to Ashgabat was frankly incredible.  At
first one see a collection of modern-ish white building in the haze. As you get
closer you see architecture that looks like it came out of Star Wars. Tbh I
quite like the look, but it&#39;s just scarily unbelievable. I guess this might be
like Dubai. Most buildings looked wholly unoccupied... ummm this doesn&#39;t make
sense. [The heat of this city might mean that folks stay out of sight though.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We drove in convoy with the Icelandic team and we were really worried about
getting our car fined since it was dirty. There is just too much weird stuff in
Turkmenistan for me to give it justice in this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over dinner with the Icelanders we remarked how odd if was to see a women&#39;s
hair and legs (the Russian speaking waitresses) after sipping some Baltika no.7
and clinking some local Vodka. Iran had affected us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to quickly mention we met another team called &quot;Mongols to Mongolia&quot; in
the hotel restaurant which I found delightful. They are the first team of
Mongolians doing the rally from London back to their home Mongolia!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a ton of cool video and pictures to upload, but sadly despite checking
into a recommended LP top pick with Internet. The internet is even WORSE than
Iran (FB, twitter etc. are filtered also), which is a remarkable achievement. I
really hope by Uzbekistan things improve, so we can share more. Also we have
absolutely no roaming on our phones (emergency calls only), so please email us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good night... when I wake up... Believe you me it&#39;s going to be one of those
WTF moments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


	<comments>/posts/Ashgabat/#comments</comments>

</item>
<item>
	<title>Astana</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Astana/</guid>

	<link>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Astana/</link>



	<category>Kazakhstan</category>

	<category>jamie</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 07:46:10 +0100</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-08-31T05:22:30Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;The drive to Astana was very long but fairly uneventful. If you have a look at
&lt;a href=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/map/&quot;&gt;the map&lt;/a&gt; you can see we drove around a very large lake in the south of the
country, which was an absolutely &lt;a href=&quot;https://maps.google.com/?ll=45.759859,76.168213&amp;amp;spn=4.522295,9.854736&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;z=7&amp;amp;vpsrc=6&quot;&gt;beautiful perfect turquoise colour&lt;/a&gt;, not unlike
the Kazakh flag, maybe that&#39;s where it comes from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Darkness fell between 7 and 8 when we still had a considerable distance to go.
By that point we&#39;d driven for about 12 hours and covered about 3/4 of the
1100km (passing our 10,000th mile on the way). Passing through Karagandy there
were a couple of signed detours along surprisingly bad roads, considering that
we were travelling from Kazakhstan&#39;s biggest city to its capital. At one point
I was following a couple of cars along a flyover when they drove around a small
road block. I followed, not thinking much of it. Then we came to another road
block and both cars turned off the road. I followed. The road got smaller and
smaller until it was barely a dusty track. We crossed several railway tracks.
Kai started to freak out. Just as I was beginning to wonder if we should turn
around we found tarmac again, and eventually met the main road again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incredible. Relief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reaching Astana at midnight we managed to find a hotel very quickly, and went
straight to bed. We&#39;d been driving for 16 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stories of Astana we&#39;d heard in Almaty led me to imagine something along
the lines of Ashgabat, lots of new but empty and useless/already fading
buildings. But actually it was pretty normal as things go. Kai and I went to
see the Norman Foster &quot;tent&quot; this morning. It looked disappointedly small from
the outside, but it does manage to contain a six story shopping mall. As a
measure of how bright it is here, I took a picture &lt;em&gt;inside&lt;/em&gt; the shopping mall
at ISO 100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re now rushin&#39; to Russia. We&#39;ll probably camp tonight, hopefully inside
Russia, and make Novosibirsk tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/6107553957/&quot; title=&quot;Norman Foster&#39;s Astana Tent by Jamie Kitson, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6196/6107553957_fd6d88a8db.jpg&quot; width=&quot;331&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;Norman Foster&#39;s Astana Tent&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


	<comments>/posts/Astana/#comments</comments>

</item>
<item>
	<title>Bulgaria to Turkey</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Bulgaria_to_Turkey/</guid>

	<link>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Bulgaria_to_Turkey/</link>



	<category>Istanbul</category>

	<category>bulgaria</category>

	<category>kai</category>

	<category>turkey</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 07:46:10 +0100</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-08-05T04:56:51Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;349&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/U0sJxuT2txQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bulgaria was surprisingly OK. For me it&#39;s a strange mix of Russian (they
understand it, unlike the Romanians seemingly) and France (cute rustic
buildings and amazing countryside). Food is pretty bad and I&#39;m totally
unconvinced on Bulgarian&#39;s sense of taste and style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Varna and resorts to the south seemed popular for the English tourists and to
be honest the prices and women are quite attractive. Ahem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we quickly did the UNESCO tourist trap of Nessebar and headed into Turkey.
Border crossing was great... friendly staff and an initial hiccup with their
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/kaihendry/status/98788319923666944&quot;&gt;computer failing&lt;/a&gt;.
What a super drive. The scenery was stunning and dropping into Turkey was like
entering another world. Fantastic scenery.  Awesome sunset. Incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turkish roads and infrastructure seem amazingly good. We were a little worried
we forgot the &lt;a
href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vignette_(road_tax)&quot;&gt;Vignette&lt;/a&gt;, though we
picked up a KSG Auto-bahn card at a petrol station. We were easily averaging
100km/h and we made it into Istanbul with the help of Google maps... without
incident. Nuts. [Good driving, huh? - Jamie]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 50EUR per night twin room hostel in Istanbul&#39;s Sultanahmet is a bit poor
value for money to say the least.  There seems to be a chasm between &quot;hostel&quot;
and &quot;hotel&quot; and it&#39;s really hard to bridge it. I am not interested really in
talking with tourists from UK and the West [unless they&#39;re good looking]. I&#39;m
more keen to chat with locals.  A decent wifi Internet connection would be nice
too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/6008557642/&quot; title=&quot;In Istanbul, not Constantinople&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6004/6008557642_9a60a54644_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;424&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today the weather is pretty hot, though I&#39;ve got the Blue Mosque, the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/6007851939/&quot;&gt;bath&lt;/a&gt; and the Sofia Mosque
out the way and I&#39;m feeling pretty weak and dazed. There is a lot of history
here which makes me feel a little depressed tbh. Life is incredibly short in
the scheme of things and I worry a bit how I fit in...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frustratingly Google Maps does not work (very strange) and we don&#39;t have a map
of Iran*. Can&#39;t help but feel our lack of planning ahead is catching up with us.
And finding information with a shit internet connection in Istanbul is crazy
hard compared to London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Must thank Ruth who I contacted to help find some accommodation in Turkey for
us. I did another &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/kaihendry/status/99104332758265857&quot;&gt;shout
out&lt;/a&gt; for help
tomorrow, wonder if anyone gets it (Folks did!!
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/TurkeyTourismUK/status/99108049226186755&quot;&gt;Thank&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/ED8617/status/99145705771376640&quot;&gt;you&lt;/a&gt; ). I guess we
should just chance it, but it could easily cost us a lot of time. I&#39;m keen to
spend 2-3 days in Tehran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve had the epiphany that Istanbul is well... the centre of the world. They
way it bridges continents and the understated Black and Aegean sea. It&#39;s just
insanely strategic. I want Turkey in the EU. &lt;img src=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* Jamie: After going to multiple bookshops and drawing a complete blank on
Iranian maps I was advised by a tourist agency to try the Iranian Consulate. I
pictured an office block, but arriving I found a gated community. Nervous I
asked the Turkish policeman on guard whether it was alright to bother them, he
said yes and upon entering I found a small man, who understood enough English
to give me a map of attractions. It doesn&#39;t have any roads on it but it&#39;s
better than nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


	<comments>/posts/Bulgaria_to_Turkey/#comments</comments>

</item>
<item>
	<title>Campbell Irvine Mongol Rally Insurance</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Campbell_Irvine_Mongol_Rally_Insurance/</guid>

	<link>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Campbell_Irvine_Mongol_Rally_Insurance/</link>



	<category>campbell irvine</category>

	<category>insurance</category>

	<category>jamie</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 07:46:10 +0100</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-07-12T15:21:56Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Campbell Irvine is the de facto travel insurance firm for the Mongol Rally. When I contacted them I was quoted £117 for 45 days or £142 for 62 days. Kai then got wind of an annual (maximum 70 day) policy for £99. Having enquired there apparently is nothing extra included in the more expensive, shorter periods of insurance, so I requested, and received, a refund. It&#39;s a bit of a con if you ask me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jamie&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


	<comments>/posts/Campbell_Irvine_Mongol_Rally_Insurance/#comments</comments>

</item>
<item>
	<title>Car Work Videos</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Car_Work_Videos/</guid>

	<link>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Car_Work_Videos/</link>



	<category>car</category>

	<category>repairs</category>

	<category>video</category>

	<category>work</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 07:46:10 +0100</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-07-21T17:40:41Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;Just put together a couple of videos of work we&#39;ve done to our Micra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;385&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/L8nNlFtYJyc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is Josh putting together our sump guard. I think we need a bit more talking/commentary, but you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe class=&quot;youtube-player&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;385&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IWTkzsmV13g&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second is me attempting to change the oil and oil filter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;How it ended up doing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xeDinnb-vts&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


	<comments>/posts/Car_Work_Videos/#comments</comments>

</item>
<item>
	<title>Computer adventures</title>

	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Computer_adventures/</guid>

	<link>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Computer_adventures/</link>



	<category>England</category>


	<pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 07:46:10 +0100</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2011-06-24T07:47:24Z</dcterms:modified>


	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/rcfl/5837798020/&quot; title=&quot;Team Geekout by rufie c, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.static.flickr.com/2456/5837798020_9b5524cc5b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;Team Geekout&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/about/&quot;&gt;Jamie and I&lt;/a&gt; spend a lot of time looking at computer screens in order
to prepare for this adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


	<comments>/posts/Computer_adventures/#comments</comments>

</item>

</channel>
</rss>
