<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>blog</title>
<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/blog/"/>
<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/blog/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>Team Geekout (Jamie&Kai) geeked out on the Mongol Rally 2011</name>

</author>




<id>https://geekout.org.uk/blog/</id>

<subtitle type="html">Team Geekout (Jamie&amp;Kai) geeked out on the Mongol Rally 2011</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>Kit debrief</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Kit_debrief/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Kit_debrief/"/>






	<category term="kai" />

	<category term="kit" />


	<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
	<published>2011-09-21T03:06:12Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;If I can scan the &lt;a href=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/kit/&quot;&gt;kit&lt;/a&gt; list of what we brought, I thought I should extol
which was good and what was a waste of space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The good&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Tomtom &amp;amp; Google Maps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cheated. Team Geekout relied heavily on GPS for navigation during the Mongol
Rally. The Tomtom saved us hours in Europe until it stopped working as we
entered Ukraine. From that point on Google maps helped us, except for a fairly
&lt;a href=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/posts/The_Perils_of_using_Google_maps/&quot;&gt;entertaining instance&lt;/a&gt; in Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise we didn&#39;t use it for turn by turn navigation, just as a guide to
ensure we were going to the right direction on the right road. The new-ish
Google maps pre-cache map area looked cool, but since you can&#39;t search offline
I must say it sucked. Especially in big crazy cities like Tehran. It was better than nothing though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of annoying seething bugs in Google maps for Android, like when you
accidentally press the back button and lose current navigation. So sometimes I
would switch to using the Iphone4&#39;s Google maps application, or use both and as
both would somehow have different levels of cache of the same road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Spot connect&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/6177975222/&quot; title=&quot;IMG_0234 by Kai Hendry, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6153/6177975222_fbac1512b0_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;179&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_0234&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite my initial apprehensions, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.globaltelesat.co.uk/satphone/SPOT_Connect.html#a288&quot;&gt;SPOT
connect&lt;/a&gt;
actually worked rather well. The device demands &lt;a href=&quot;https://faq.findmespot.com/index.php?action=showEntry&amp;amp;data=1330&quot;&gt;lithium
batteries&lt;/a&gt;
which are frankly impossible to source. Normal Alkaline Duracell lasted about 2
working days and cheap Chinese ones, less than a day. Which was very annoying.
It does have a mini-USB slot underneath it and looks like it could be powered
by it, but it didn&#39;t seem to work frustratingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the clunky client and UI, the SPOT tracklog worked and we now have a
fantastic &lt;a href=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/map/&quot;&gt;tracklog of our journey&lt;/a&gt;. Was that worth
300GBP despite fact one could collate GPS tracklogs?! I think so... because it
kept our followers engaged in realtime. It was also handy in the very rare
instances our mobiles or Jamie&#39;s kindle didn&#39;t work to send a little 41
character message out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Our blogging platform, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.branchable.com/&quot;&gt;Branchable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many other Mongol rally teams failed to get past one or two blogs. Jamie and I
blogged continuously through the trip... How? Without an internet connection?
We used &lt;strong&gt;git&lt;/strong&gt; to commit blogs, and when we had internet in the briefest of
moments we pushed and our readership got to enjoy our updates! Other blogging
platforms basically assume you are on the Internet whilst writing the post,
which sucks. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.branchable.com/&quot;&gt;Branchable&lt;/a&gt; powered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://ikiwiki.info/&quot;&gt;Ikiwiki&lt;/a&gt; rocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Kindle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jamie has talked about this before in numerous tweets and FB updates. Amazingly
this device kept him connected in every country bar Turkmenistan,
though it was a bit flaky through the &#39;stans. From our experience &lt;a href=&quot;https://client0.cellmaps.com/viewer.html?cov=2&amp;amp;view=intl&quot;&gt;Amazon&#39;s coverage map&lt;/a&gt; seems quite accurate. Incredibly useful. I will
purchase the next update myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/forum/kindle?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;cdForum=Fx1D7SY3BVSESG&amp;amp;cdThread=Tx390HFZ5SRXHJ6&quot;&gt;newer &quot;Touch&quot; Kindles will not offer free 3G browsing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://moo.com/products/business-cards.html&quot;&gt;Moo business cards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could have printed my mobile number though, otherwise super useful. Expensive
unreliable mobile calls were the no. 1 way teams communicated unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Vegabond Systems Source Widepac Water bladder 3L in the micra&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/6177481443/&quot; title=&quot;IMG_0395 by Kai Hendry, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6176/6177481443_c3149902b8_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;179&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_0395&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this bladder, although Jamie correctly pointed out we could just use
water bottles. I liked it because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We could hang it off the headrest behind the passenger seat and have the tube
sit around the handbrake, in easy reach of hydration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One could hydrate while keeping both hands on the steering wheel and have clear vision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We kept it in hot countries in a cooler box with ice, so it delivered cool water all day (You can actually freeze the whole damn thing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3L typically holds two plastic water bottles and it&#39;s less unsightly than keeping bottle upon bottle in the car&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It did exhibit problems after hard use. Later in the car journey it fealt a bit
gassy, as we sucked there seemed to be air coming in from somewhere. Near the
very end of the journey the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/6167704999/&quot;&gt;Widepac started to
leak&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;img src=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/smileys/sad.png&quot; alt=&quot;:(&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/SourceOutdoor&quot;&gt;SourceOutdoor&lt;/a&gt; replaced the
Widepac and threw in a Spresh. I highly recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceoutdoor.com/&quot;&gt;Source
Outdoor&lt;/a&gt; products!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Korean cooker&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/5973188757/&quot; title=&quot;We got gas by Kai Hendry, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6016/5973188757_54f5b365ed_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; alt=&quot;We got gas&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It amazes me how many different camping stove non-standards there are. I
recommend the Korean gas cooker. It&#39;s not great if you are hiking since it fits
in a bulky looking briefcase. Though if you are in a car, it&#39;s perfect. The
butane gas canisters are the easiest fuel source to obtain practically anywhere
in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must also mention that our Korean Nong Shim ramen &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/5872491113/&quot;&gt;we
bought&lt;/a&gt;, esp. with an egg is a
much better meal than some of this dehydrated protein ration packs we saw other
teams use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Crafty Plugger&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jamie was dubious as to how well the Crafty Plugger would work on a puncture caused by a stone, but we used it on the one puncture we had after the Pamir Highway and it was very quick and easy and worked very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Non-Slip Mat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jamie laughed at Kai for buying the non-slip mat, but has to admit that it was pretty useful, until Kai lost it. It was one of Geekout&#39;s lowest days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;GoPro Hero HD&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GoPro was going strong, until we ran it over. The camera itself was undamaged (despite getting wet) but the sucker mount was broken beyond repair and the clip holding the main case together was broken. We resorted to one of the sticky mounts and tape respectively. Unfortunately I didn&#39;t realise that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GA-BvymgNxI#t=0m25s&quot;&gt;the white rubber bit is for damping those mounts&lt;/a&gt;, and consequently the audio is pretty much useless, and the video not much better. The angle that it shot from the dashboard was pretty bad too, I should have taken the plunge and stuck it straight onto the windscreen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GoPro UI is pretty simple, just two buttons. However if you don&#39;t use it much and can&#39;t see the light or hear the beeps, or know what the beeps mean, then it can be difficult to know what/if the button you have just pressed has done. Hence we have a lot of recordings of quizzical faces looming into view to check that it&#39;s recording. I personally found it difficult to remember which button did what when the camera was upside down. It also wasn&#39;t much cop in darker conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The battery would last for approximately two to three hours, which was enough, the problem was that the battery meter was practically useless, it would sink from three bars to empty in minutes, meaning that we had to either remember how much we had used it, or just charge it whenever we could. Strangely the GoPro seemed to use almost as much battery while on but not doing anything as it did when it was actually filming. While it does have a battery meter, there is no meter at all for available space on the SD card, which is something that GoPro really needs to address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;HTC Double USB Car Adapter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very useful and lasted the entire journey. In fact it was probably one of the most reliable things we, erm, relied on. Especially once Jamie had taped it up with the cigarette lighter splitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Kelly Kettle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/6148440822/&quot; title=&quot;My Dung is on Fire by Jamie Kitson, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.staticflickr.com/6203/6148440822_0d8f1f53db_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;159&quot; alt=&quot;My Dung is on Fire&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Kelly Kettle was very good at what it did, boiling water, quickly and efficiently. We could have used it a bit more if we&#39;d camped more, it wasn&#39;t great in desert conditions, unless you could find some dung. I have to admit that it was a bit bulky and didn&#39;t pack-up that well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The bad&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ortliebusa.com/CartGenie/prod-66.htm&quot;&gt;Ortlieb 10L water bladder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to love the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/5973382943/&quot;&gt;10L Ortlieb water
bladder&lt;/a&gt; I bought in Dresden.
Unfortunately the tap became far too stiff and it leaked. The rubber ring was
far too easy to dislodge I suspect. Also the straps could be far more
comfortable to carry. Pity it sucked compared to my wonderful Ortlieb pannier
which I took with my on the Mongol rally for keeping my documents and laptop in
shape!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Sony ICF-7600D&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in uproar when I heard BBC were suspending shortwave broadcasts, though
honestly trying to use my shortwave kit whilst Jamie was say reading the
Guardian on the Kindle, made me think... maybe the world has moved on. I did
catch &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/fromourowncorrespondent/&quot;&gt;FOOC&lt;/a&gt; once in Iran, but I
could have downloaded the podcast in a number of previous opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortwave broadcasts still work in the Afghanistan region and I wish I could
jettison my kit there somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And going back to Iran, their Internet needs improving... I wonder if
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tooway.com/&quot;&gt;Tooway&lt;/a&gt; could maybe made to work in Tehran. That would
be cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Iphone4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love the quality of video and how easy it is to mail off photographs on the
move. It has some bad sides, like how do I now update the &quot;Standard Definition&quot;
video uploads with &quot;High Definition&quot; videos now that I&#39;m on a better internet
connection? Suck...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Travelling with two passports&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jamie had two passports. One had four valid visas in that Jamie needed for the
trip, but which was full up and had been invalidated by the passport office by
having the corner removed. The other passport was fully valid and had my three
remaining visas in.  Generally this wasn&#39;t a problem, surprisingly especially
at borders. More often it was local police that saw an opportunity for a bribe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The ugly&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;PowerMonkey Explorer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought the &quot;PowerMonkey Explorer&quot; which I was excited about at first and it
stopped working on day 2. Although &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#x69;&amp;#x6C;&amp;#x74;&amp;#x6F;:&amp;#101;&amp;#109;&amp;#x69;&amp;#108;&amp;#121;&amp;#64;&amp;#x70;&amp;#x6F;&amp;#x77;&amp;#x65;&amp;#x72;t&amp;#x72;&amp;#x61;&amp;#x76;&amp;#101;&amp;#x6C;&amp;#108;&amp;#x65;&amp;#114;&amp;#46;&amp;#99;&amp;#x6F;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#101;&amp;#109;&amp;#x69;&amp;#108;&amp;#121;&amp;#64;&amp;#x70;&amp;#x6F;&amp;#x77;&amp;#x65;&amp;#x72;t&amp;#x72;&amp;#x61;&amp;#x76;&amp;#101;&amp;#x6C;&amp;#108;&amp;#x65;&amp;#114;&amp;#46;&amp;#99;&amp;#x6F;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt; provided good
customer service, she could have told me: &quot;Send to this address and we will
re-imburse you&quot;. It takes two backpack pouches and I ended up carrying it
needlessly for 20k kms, which is madness. I seeth with hate when I accidentally
open one of my pouches and all it&#39;s bit and bobs fall out. The device was
completely unnecessary since we had a 2 Slot micro-USB car charger anyway.
Avoid!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;CB radio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/5976788789/&quot; title=&quot;#mongolrally folks with CB radios, we are on EU 23 by Kai Hendry, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6147/5976788789_5dc3d05a95_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; alt=&quot;#mongolrally folks with CB radios, we are on EU 23&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This 50GBP kit I ended up giving away in Ulaanbatar because I couldn&#39;t sell it.
Later as I took a taxi to the airport, I did realise he was using a CB radio
and I therefore should have pitched my wares to a Taxi firm.  We used it once
with Rick on the road out of Goodwood. Since that we found no other team with
such communication kit. It&#39;s a far better idea to buy good quality small walky
talkies. I recommend the Motorola T8s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Jerry can&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You seriously don&#39;t need a jerry can on the Mongol rally. Petrol in a can
expands and it&#39;s often pressurized when you open it. The vapour can easily
ignite and can leave you in &lt;a href=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Khovd_to_Altay__44___Mongolia/&quot;&gt;a very dangerous situation&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Spare shock absorber&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We lugged around a spare Micra shock absorber. Wtf Jamie. WTF? &lt;img src=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt; [It was about
as heavy and bulky as your pillow, you pussy :P] Spares like the air filter
were unnecessary as you can easily knock the dust out of a filter on the move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Car Cigarette Lighter Socket Splitter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tried two of these, we didn&#39;t even bother taking the 4-way (bottom right &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/5849953365/in/datetaken/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, detail &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/5943368019/in/datetaken/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/5950819915/in/datetaken/&quot;&gt;the 2-way&lt;/a&gt; was still very annoying and Jamie ended up taping it right up in order to stop it cutting out on bumpy roads. If we&#39;d been using the CB radio we would have needed it, but as it was the double USB adapter we had was enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;What we didn&#39;t take&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Mains USB Charger&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we didn&#39;t really miss it I recently bought &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.play.com/PC/PCs/4-/15403175/Kensington-4-Port-USB-Mains-Charger-Ref-K38035EU/Product.html?_%24ja=tsid:11518|cat:15403175|prd:15403175&quot;&gt;a 4 port mains USB charger&lt;/a&gt; which handily comes with both UK and EU plugs, which would have been very handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;External Microphones&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of cheapish external mics for iPhones, any of which I&#39;m sure would have improved our audio iPhone recordings no end. One particular problem was that it seemed quite easy for Kai to cover the mic with his hand meaning we got virtually no audio at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I assume that we could have also attached an external mic to the GoPro, whose audio is even worse than the iPhone&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Kit_debrief/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Kit_debrief/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>
<entry>
	<title>A Message To Our Sponsors</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/A_Message_To_Our_Sponsors/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/A_Message_To_Our_Sponsors/"/>






	<category term="jamie" />

	<category term="sponsorship" />


	<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
	<published>2011-09-12T09:09:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;letter&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hello!
&lt;p&gt;
First of all thank you very much for your sponsorship, it was much
appreciated by Kai and I as it allowed us to get off on our little
jaunt, and I&#39;m sure it will be appreciated almost as much by our two
charities, Amnesty International and the Christina Noble Children&#39;s
Foundation in Mongolia. The current total is £1570, though since we&#39;ve
finished we&#39;ve had a small flurry of donations.
&lt;p&gt;
Now on to what you have all been waiting for, the results! We arrived
at the finish line at approximately 4:57pm Mongolia time on Thursday
8th September, which I make 6 weeks, 4 days, 18 hours and 57 minutes,
having done 12,566 miles, or 20,223 km.
&lt;p&gt;
In the distance guess Rachel gets a special mention, as the only
person to overestimate, however we didn&#39;t quite hit the 30,000 mile
mark I&#39;m afraid Rachel. Claudio&#39;s guess of 8425 miles was just pipped
by Sara and Rob&#39;s guess of 8454.4 miles. As Claudio said, we certainly
did more miles than planned.
&lt;p&gt;
In the time guess Larry and Gez both predicted 4th September, just
four days off, but my sister Maddy (Sara and Rob&#39;s niece, keeping it
in the family) managed a guess just 16 hours out!
&lt;p&gt;
Prizes will be distributed to those two lucky, or skilled, winners,
but if the rest of you would like to send me your address I will post
you a (very small) token of our appreciation.
&lt;p&gt;
The rally itself went pretty well for us, if you haven&#39;t been keeping
up our blog is at https://geekout.org.uk/ and a map of our trip is
here: https://geekout.org.uk/map/
&lt;p&gt;
Back to work for me tomorrow.
&lt;p&gt;
Thanks again, Jamie
&lt;/div&gt;
If you&#39;ve enjoyed our updates, and haven&#39;t already, maybe it&#39;s time to think about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justgiving.com/teams/geekout/&quot;&gt;donating&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/A_Message_To_Our_Sponsors/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/A_Message_To_Our_Sponsors/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Ulaanbatar</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Ulaanbatar/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Ulaanbatar/"/>






	<category term="kai" />

	<category term="mongolia" />


	<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
	<published>2011-09-11T03:40:16Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/6122868184/&quot; title=&quot;The Goat skull talisman&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6210/6122868184_db6cf7e936.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;331&quot; alt=&quot;Geekout mascot&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&#39;m alone now, no Icelanders or &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamiek.it/&quot;&gt;Jamie&lt;/a&gt; to entertain myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I was aiming to watch the Rugby world cup, though whilst trying to
find the recommended expat bar Casablanca at Hotel Bayangor in Ulaanbaatar, I
was invited to ride on a bus with the Uzbekistan national Judo team to the Judo
World Cup. I accepted the offer and it made my day. Took me some time to
understand how the points were scored, the most important one is when you
manage to fling your opponent on their back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opening ceremony was weird at first with a Ghinggis Kahn brigade on horses
crapping everywhere. The second phase was a parade of participating countries,
however none of the participating countries athletes actually paraded. Only
Mongolians holding the flags of the countries, which I thought was a bit odd.
The final part of the opening ceremony was the best. It had some Mongolians
dancing and I took a video, which I&#39;ll share here later TODO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left after 3 hours of entertainment to try catch the second half of the
England/Argentina rugby game. This was a mistake and I was stuck in traffic for
an hour since a vehicle hit a passing train. UB&#39;s traffic problems are frankly
bonkers, when trains intersect key roads (like the one from the airport), you
just have to wonder what idiot came up with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did catch the last minutes of the rugby game to see England scrape through. I
then wondered around town like an alien and settled on a huge UB burger for
dinner.  I then tried to play Counter Strike with the locals but there were
frustrating problems with joining the server, so I spend the rest of the
evening reading Wikipedia about Mongolian history, dress and combat strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Random thoughts about Mongolia&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This probably applies to any country that uses the Cyrillic alphabet, though I
find it extremely annoying how the latin / english versions of place names vary
in spelling. You might have noticed some inconsistencies in our posts. This
makes it really hard to search for things at times. I probably need to read
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Romanization_of_Russian&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Romanization_of_Russian&lt;/a&gt; and weep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still something like Ulaanba(a)tar or &quot;Ghinggis Kahn&quot; could be consistently
spelled could it not? Variations for example could be Genghis Khan, or Khaan.
Nightmare!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s the deal with the random swastika symbols in UB?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why can&#39;t these people negotiate like other Asian countries?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why have Mongolian people on two occassions just given me money?&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Ulaanbatar/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Ulaanbatar/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Unofficial Payments</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Unofficial_Payments/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Unofficial_Payments/"/>






	<category term="bribes" />

	<category term="jamie" />


	<updated>2012-06-25T09:45:45Z</updated>
	<published>2011-09-11T03:05:26Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;ie, Bribes. The best technique seems to be waiting for a) official boredom, b) more money making opportunities to turn up, eg, tourists c) somebody higher up in the chain to come along, eg, military vs police.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Country&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Asked for&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Paid&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ukraine&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;€100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;€30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Supposedly doing 80kph in a 50kph zone. Possibly true.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ukraine&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;€40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;€20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Not stopping at a stop sign. The trouble was there was a massive truck in the way of the sign, if there was a sign.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Iran&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Multiool (€30)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;T-shirt and tea&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Official at the border kept asking for gifts. Wished we hadn&#39;t given him anything after below.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Iran&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;€20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;€10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Burly man at the border who we didn&#39;t want to piss off too much.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Iran&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Caught speeding, but let off with a warning &lt;img src=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Turkmenistan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Caught speeding as the police put up temporary speed limit signs, in this case 30kph, which was honestly difficult to read.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Uzbekistan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This was actually official, I even got a receipt! But it was still ridiculous. I was fined for driving too quickly through the &quot;disinfectant&quot; at the border. There was no way I caused all the puddles that they were pointing at, tbh, I think the team that went before me might have done it, but we both got fined. We didn&#39;t stop at the stop sign, a recurring theme.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Uzbekistan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;£1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kai caught speeding. Let off after trying out speed gun and a misunderstanding about a &quot;gift&quot;, Kai insisted on going back and giving him a souvenir pound coin. The policeman did not look impressed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Passport officials. Stupidly paid without thinking.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Car insurance, or possibly customs. I think $25 was the proper sum, but we were asked for $45.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Have a feeling that the last two guys that dealt with us wanted something?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Police check at the border. I was going to the car to get some money but they got bored and we just left.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Up to €100 down to $20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Police check point just looking for a reason to take money from us. First they made something up about our visas. We were patient and explained again and again that our visas were ok. When they got bored of that they let Mud-Lab go and started on me and my invalid passport. They were just insisting on $20 when a military guy walked passed outside and they suddenly took our $10 and let us go. I kind of wished I&#39;d snatched the $10, run outside and waved it in their face from the window. But I didn&#39;t.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;


&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tajikistan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$25 x 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10 for both cars.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Customs leaving Tajikistan. This seemed to be a tried and trusted scam, telling us that we were missing the customs receipt from entering (see above). It may even be that customs delierately didn&#39;t give us a receipt when we entered. We were let off for $10 only when two more teams arrived and were subjected to the same treatment.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kyrgyzstan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Thought I&#39;d mention this as I was very pleased not to be asked at the border as the guards were looking very serious and very dubious about the visa in my old, invalid passport.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kyrgyzstan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10 + 100 Somme ($3?)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kai caught speeding early in the morning, apparently still within the limits of a town.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kyrgyzstan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;All our old Uzbek money, about $20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Caught speeding again, same day.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kyrgyzstan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10 between two cars&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Same day. Not stopping at a stop sign, *just* before the Kazakh border.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kazakhstan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Accidentally left border into Kazakhstan and needed to get back in to Kai and the car. Was brazenly asked for $10 but didn&#39;t pay and met Kai outside.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Russia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;100 Rubles I think, about $3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Immigration officer just asked as we were leaving, we acted confused and after a few minutes let us go.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mongolia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;100 Rubles, about $3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;For disinfecting the car. Other teams said they had to pay $1 and got a receipt.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mongolia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The guy who searched our car (with a very cute dog in a very cute coat) just asked, and we just gave.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Total&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;About $310&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;About $180&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;

&lt;/table&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Unofficial_Payments/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Unofficial_Payments/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>
<entry>
	<title>The Finish line</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/The_Finish_line/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/The_Finish_line/"/>






	<category term="kai" />

	<category term="mongolia" />


	<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
	<published>2011-09-10T05:08:16Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;h1&gt;Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tarmacked road from Arvaikheer was pretty uneventful. There were some bad
patches with huge potholes that would probably shock most European drivers, but
by this time Jamie and I have seen (and possibly hit) every state of road
detriment possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/6129217831/&quot; title=&quot;Last camp lunch by Kai Hendry, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6210/6129217831_8dcd4b4194.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;374&quot; alt=&quot;Last camp lunch&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/kaihendry/status/111674161436434432&quot;&gt;ate some dry food packs from the
Icelanders&lt;/a&gt; and I
must say they were awful compared to Nong Shim with an egg. I am going to miss
our little camp lunches on our butane powered Korean stove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we entered Ulaanbaatar we had to navigate bad roads and a ton of traffic.
Painfully but surely we found the Adventurist Mongol Rally finish line. Of
course it was a little anti-climatic. There was no one there to greet us.
Though a fellow rallier who finished a week before, Kathleen from
&lt;a href=&quot;https://teamrecklessabandon.org/&quot;&gt;https://teamrecklessabandon.org/&lt;/a&gt; was passing and congratulated us and gave
us some advice where to stay and eat etc, which was helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/6129766746/&quot; title=&quot;Our little finish line celebration dinner at a North Korean rest by Kai Hendry, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6196/6129766746_877a177b23.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;374&quot; alt=&quot;Our little finish line celebration dinner at a North Korean rest&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We settled on Seoul Hotel, checked in and then went for a Korean meal.
Other teams like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theadventurists.com/the-adventures/mongol-rally/teams/TeamBear&quot;&gt;Team
Bear&lt;/a&gt;
joined us and surprisingly the restaurant served items from &lt;strong&gt;North Korea&lt;/strong&gt;. Joviality ensued
and I thought it was quite a good celebratory dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later we went to an Irish bar and drank some more. Delightfully I received a call
over Skype from the Icelanders. They had been in town since the morning! They
had taken an overnight bus from Bayankhongor and actually beat us to UB by
several hours.  However they recalled the 15 person minibus carrying 21 people
and a lot of luggage, how cold it was and their &quot;brace ball&quot; position they
adopted for the 13hr journey. So we met at the State department store which is
by far the easiest landmark in UB and went back to Irish bar... to drink some
more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became pretty drunk and ended up in some over-forties live music joint a taxi
ride away with Thor &amp;amp; Egill. We suitably partied the night away and entertained
quite a hangover the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/The_Finish_line/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/The_Finish_line/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Arvaikheer</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Arvaikheer/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Arvaikheer/"/>






	<category term="Mongolia" />

	<category term="kai" />


	<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
	<published>2011-09-10T04:28:55Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/6129218995/&quot; title=&quot;Cold in Mongolia by Kai Hendry, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6066/6129218995_e8d6a54a4e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;374&quot; alt=&quot;Cold in Mongolia&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We towed the Peugeot 306 to the drop off point in Bayanhongor and said goodbye
to the Icelanders. &lt;img src=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/smileys/sad.png&quot; alt=&quot;:(&quot; /&gt;  They were going to catch a bus and meet us in UB
(Ulaanbaatar).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Altai to Bayanhongor definitely seemed like the &lt;strong&gt;hardest stretch&lt;/strong&gt; and we saw
5 or 6 cars at the drop off point that also didn&#39;t finish.  We ate our last
packet of Nong Shim Ramen from the 20 pack box I bought back in New Malden and
we got underway by 2pm. I was quite worried we might be pushing our luck as we
had been told that it would take 4-5hrs to get to Arvaikheer. Thankfully the
weather was fine, most of the snow seemed to disappear and we made it in
4.5hrs. This was our last piece of dirt road, since we knew the next leg was
all sealed. How I am going to miss those &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/6129220415/&quot;&gt;Mongolian
roads&lt;/a&gt;, they were really good
fun. Intense concentration was required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we arrived in Arvaikheer with an hour of sunlight left, so we thought we had
plenty of time to evaluate its hotels. The first one was a building site
outside, but was warm and an OK standard, but a bit dear at ~40USD. The next
place didn&#39;t have its heating on and it had a policemen&#39;s party on the floor
below. You could clearly hear the excruciating Karaoke from below. The next
places were shitholes and we were directed by a Mongolian guide to a couple of
other hotels, but we frustratingly couldn&#39;t find them. After an hour I thought
we should go for the very first hotel, only to find the room was now
unavailable.  Tired, cold, hungry and frustrated. Not a good combination. So we
settled on the place with the Karaoke and we told it would finish by 11pm.
Which it did actually, thankfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we tried to find food and we did find a place with a waitress who was about
16 but amazingly could speak English. We ate dinner and breakfast there.
Breakfast is a nerve racking affair in Mongolia. I am in wonder how they will
screw up the eggs. Broken? Stone cold? Anything is possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I almost forgot to mention we went next door to a night club called &quot;New
Leader&quot; in Arvaikheer. It was cold, the sound system sounded like the speakers
were all blown. The music was a bit hardcore and there tables of mostly hard
looking men ordering a beer for each and a large bottle of vodka for the table. No doubt
people were going to get seriously drunk!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway Arvaikheer was our last night on the road and I was miserable, I hope
you can tell by reading this. &lt;img src=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/smileys/smile4.png&quot; alt=&quot;;)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Arvaikheer/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Arvaikheer/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Altay to Bayankhongor&#44; Mongolia</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Altay_to_Bayankhongor__44___Mongolia/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Altay_to_Bayankhongor__44___Mongolia/"/>






	<category term="jamie" />

	<category term="mongolia" />


	<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
	<published>2011-09-07T04:19:42Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;We travelled for most of the day in convoy with the five other teams, having
fun with the driving, sliding around and racing each other. Micras are
definitely well suited to Mongolian roads, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mud-lab.com&quot;&gt;Mud Lab&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s 1.6L
Peugeot 306 the only one able to keep up with the two Micras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch Kai and I and Mud Lab broke away from the four other teams and made
it into Altay, Mud Lab running low on both fuel and money. We milled around in the town for a bit, picking up some supplies
&amp;amp; money, Mud Lab making some more repairs. This time, worryingly, to their
brakes, having already had to fix a fuel leak on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided I was tired of noodles and fancied eating in a restaurant. A helpful
gentleman said, through a translator on the phone, that he would show us a place.
He got in our car and we literally drove around the block. He showed us a restaurant.
The guy on the phone then said we should give him 15,000 of the local currency.
Reluctantly I did. He refused asking for 20,000. By this time Kai was still sitting
in the drivers seat, but I was out of the car and the guy was blocking my way.
Eventually Kai started to drive off, I jumped in the front seat and we sped off back
to Mud Lab. Considering that it was just around the corner we were concerned that
we might have an angry Mongolian or two on our tail and were rather put off Altay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kai and I decided to go ahead and scout out potential camp sites, but when we found
how cold and windy it was went back into town to have a look at hotels. We weren&#39;t
impressed and together with Mud Lab and their newly working brakes headed out. We
aimed for what we thought could be a natural wind break over a hill, but managed to
end up in a natural wind tunnel. It started to rain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day was slow going, partially due to the bad roads, but mostly due to
Mud Lab&#39;s bad luck. (Or perhaps poor planing in choosing a Peugeot  ;).) After a
couple of hours driving they sailed over a ridge and hit the other side, blew
both airbags, dislodging their front grill and fan. As they couldn&#39;t reattach
the fan their car started to overheat at regular intervals and they would have
to stop and point their car straight into the wind for a while. Moments after
one of these stops they discovered one of their tyres had split.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards evening the wind was really getting up, causing something like a dust
storm, as we approached a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yurt&quot;&gt;gher&lt;/a&gt; camp and &lt;a
href=&quot;https://maps.google.co.uk/?ll=45.833584,99.372368&amp;amp;spn=0.072121,0.181789&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;z=13&amp;amp;vpsrc=6&quot;&gt;large
river&lt;/a&gt;. Looking at our maps it seemed that the road was on the other side of
the river. Several locals pointed us in the direction of the river and one
offered to tow us across in his tractor for $30 each. We were dubious and
waited. After a while a mini bus approached and we followed it, watching as it
crossed the river, from one island to another. We followed in its footsteps. It
was pretty nerve racking to be honest, especially as there were about four
crossings in total, two of which we hadn&#39;t seen the mini bus cross, but we made
it. I really regret not taking a picture of what greeted us, a desolate,
apocalyptic even, vision of dust caught by the sun blowing across several ghers
and virtually nothing else for as far as the eye could see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this time there was only an hour or two of sunlight left, and we&#39;d only done
about 250km of 400km, but we decided to press on. The roads got even worse and
our speed slowed and slowed as night drew in, and the wind got colder. About
40km from Bayankhongor the road started to get quite wet and muddy. About 10km
from town Mud Lab looked like they got stuck in mud. Their car sounded like it
wasn&#39;t quite in gear. Ale reckons they might have a broken Axel. We managed to
tow them out of the worst of the mud they were in, but didn&#39;t think we&#39;d make
it the 10km due to the mud, we were having difficulty getting just ourselves
out of some of it. So we left them there and went to get help. Practically over
the next hill we were able to see the lights of the town and had mobile signal
and were able to call the Adventurists hot line, but by the time we got back to
Mud Lab to give them the good news they&#39;d already managed to get a tow from a
Mongolian mining magnate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kai and I visited several hotels before picking one we liked and were just
checking in when who should turn up but Mud Lab!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was last night. We woke this morning, opened the curtains and thanked our
lucky stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s snowing!&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Altay_to_Bayankhongor__44___Mongolia/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Altay_to_Bayankhongor__44___Mongolia/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Khovd to Altay&#44; Mongolia</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Khovd_to_Altay__44___Mongolia/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Khovd_to_Altay__44___Mongolia/"/>






	<category term="jamie" />

	<category term="mongolia" />


	<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
	<published>2011-09-05T11:54:19Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Driving in Mongolia is a lot of fun. The roads tend to be very wide, usually gravelly, or if
you&#39;re really lucky very sandy and often splitting off into 2, 3 or even six different paths.
There are often obstacles, some of them moving, including camels, stones and various types of
holes, dips and ridges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent our second night in Mongolia in a gher camp setup by one of the
Mongolians actually doing the rally in Khovd. It was to be the last night of
his camp and he had already taken down most of the ghers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we started the long drive to Altay, apparently the worst bit of the Southern route
across Mongolia. I may be tempting fate here, but it really hasn&#39;t been that bad so far, more
of the above. The worst is the small, regular ridges, possibly caused by tracked vehicles in the
winter. The cars vibrate painfully, until you reach the &lt;em&gt;Sweet Spot&lt;/em&gt;. Usually at about 90kph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To our great pleasure We&#39;d met the Icelandic team, Mud Lab, yet again, in Khovd
and left with them in the morning, east. In the evening we came across two other
teams, Modern Nomads (Kit from Norway) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://hittheroadyak.com/&quot;&gt;Hit the Road
Yak&lt;/a&gt; (George and Matt) and then another two teams
that they&#39;d been in convoy with, Fear and Alexes in Mongolia (Alex, whose team
mate had had to fly to Ulan bater to get a rabies jab after being bitten by a
dog in Khovd) and &lt;a
href=&quot;https://mongolrally2011.blogspot.com/2011/09/days-forty-six-and-forty-seven-never-be.html&quot;&gt;Banana
Hammock (Heather and Justin)&lt;/a&gt;, which made six teams in total, the largest
convoy we&#39;ve travelled with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I would like to to treat the next bit like an episode of Casualty, what could possibly go wrong
in the following situation?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The four teams we&#39;d met had this game they played, called rocky rock, where
they would all throw stones at a specific rock, trying to hit it. A little
while after starting this game, &lt;s&gt;someone, George I think,&lt;/s&gt; Alex aimed a small rock at
Kit&#39;s car, hitting the back window and shattering it. Like all good geeks, he
fixed it with duct tape. Taping up the whole window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moved on. We were one of the last cars. Just after a particular sandy
section of road we found Kit and his car, pointing in the wrong direction. He&#39;d
spun and both left tyres had deflated, he decided due to the seal being broken
rather than punctures. Luckily he had two spares, changed them with us watching
and we were on our way. The other teams had stopped up ahead to camp and we
formed a bit of a circle with our wagons. Kit was determined to make a fire and
started chopping up a bit of wood he had with an axe. We joked that with the
luck he&#39;d had he shouldn&#39;t be wielding an axe.  Kit gathered some dung and
asked for some petrol. Being as my mum has always drummed into me not to use
petrol on fires I didn&#39;t volunteer our petrol and hoped he could find something
a little less flammable. The next thing we knew he was opening a very large
jerry can in the middle of the circle. For some reason the can was pressurised
and very full and sprayed petrol as it was opened.  Unfortunately one team had
already started cooking and in the moment that we all stood, staring in
disbelief the petrol ignited. Now Hollywood (and Casualty) may have lead you to
believe that the petrol on the ground will burn in a nice line until it reaches
the full can at which point the can will explode and everyone dies. Let me tell
you from experience that this is not what happens.  The spilt petrol all
ignited simultaneously, everyone ran for their lives and then there was a calm
moment as everything just burned. Luckily none of the petrol had reached the
car. Unfortunately Kit had been sprayed and was now on fire. &lt;s&gt;Someone, George I
believe&lt;/s&gt; Alex, redeeming himself from breaking Kit&#39;s back windscreen managed to put
Kit out and the rest of us stood in shock. Kai was the first to remember that
we actually had a fire extinguisher and handed it to me, later saying that he
didn&#39;t want to be the one caught in any explosion.  Kit&#39;s burns didn&#39;t seem too
bad, though obviously relatively serious and apparently very painful. Kit
happened to have set his video camera up on a tripod and filmed the whole
thing. Several of us wondered if he&#39;d done the whole thing on purpose &lt;img src=&quot;https://geekout.org.uk/smileys/smile4.png&quot; alt=&quot;;)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Khovd_to_Altay__44___Mongolia/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Khovd_to_Altay__44___Mongolia/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Altai Mongolia</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Altai_Mongolia/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Altai_Mongolia/"/>






	<category term="kai" />

	<category term="mongolia" />

	<category term="russia" />


	<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
	<published>2011-09-03T03:49:00Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;We set off for the Altai Mountains from Novosibirsk by keeping to the rather good M52 road. We
knew we were in the Altai when we started seeing these quite beautiful
mountains and accompanying rivers. There were many guest houses and some camp
spots on the way, though none seemed suitable to us. Too close to a house. Too
close to a road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As dusk fell we found ourselves in a very wet misty area of the Altai where the
road struck off from the main river. After some abortive searching we found a suitable
place, though the road was too muddy to take our Micra to our camp site. We
ended up parking the car by the road and carrying our stuff to the sodden camping
ground near a worryingly high stream. We setup just before a downpour. In the rain we cooked
Ramen and we ate it in the tent. Thunder and lightning made it a bit of a
dreary/exciting night, nonetheless I am kind of glad to have the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/6108106092/&quot; title=&quot;Breakfast Picnic and Drying by Jamie Kitson, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6086/6108106092_26c180ebf6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;331&quot; alt=&quot;Breakfast Picnic and Drying&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we were back on the M52 heading for Tashanta. After a couple of hours the damp mist lifted and a
warming sun came out. We stopped and  made eggs with
smoked wieners on the bank of a scenic [apart from all the rubish :(] river where we found out that we had been
featured in an online Nsk newspaper, being the most popular article (15,000 hits!) and even acquired a female fan! 
We laid out all our wet camping gear, which dried very quickly in the morning sun. The news, the drying and the 
breakfast all lifted our previously damp [haha] spirits and we hit the road, very keen to get into Mongolia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhat surprisingly the landscape very quickly changed from green mountainsides to light
brown sandy slopes. It looked like Mongolia all of a sudden. Usual border
crossing shenanigans entailed, including our first really thorough search upon leaving Russia,
though I felt like a veteran at this stage and I was almost sad that it was our last one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was off that the Russian immigration officer wanted 100 rubles in some
registration fee. What cheek. It was worse on the Mongolian side. A 5USD
disinfectant fee? Passport control offering to change money? Various fees from
7 to 10 dollars for god knows what. Anyhoo, we got through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a list of all the Mongol ralliers and it was interesting to see that
yes, indeed, we were one of the very last to cross.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamiekitson/6108116726/&quot; title=&quot;Mongolia by Jamie Kitson, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6205/6108116726_f3e64dd9c3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;331&quot; alt=&quot;Mongolia&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We met 2 Norwegians in a fire truck which was good. Then on the road we met the
four motorcyclists/mopedists we&#39;d met in Turkey, who&#39;d already stopped to camp. They were in good spirits and I must say
they must have had quite a strenuous rally! From the insurance office on the border
we&#39;d picked up a female hitch hiker, who later sang in our car, which provided
us some entertainment on the way to Olgii.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were keen to get to Olgii as Team America had been in touch with us, they
must have realised we were only a day behind and were looking for someone to
travel with to UB. We were too tbh, so I was glad to see their invite. We are
about to breakfast with them and they are keen to go off the beaten track and
take the more challenging &quot;Northern route&quot;. As opposed to the &quot;Southern route&quot; which the
Mongol Rally handbook seems to only mention. Tbh I am keen to do the track
other ralliers do, but then again I am brimming with confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the handbook says, fast speeds and big rocks end badly. It also mentions if
everything goes well, you should make UB in 5 days. Jamie now has 6.5 days until his
flight, so this going to be tight.&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Altai_Mongolia/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Altai_Mongolia/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Novosibirsk</title>

	<id>https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Novosibirsk/</id>

	<link href="https://geekout.org.uk/posts/Novosibirsk/"/>






	<category term="kai" />

	<category term="russia" />


	<updated>2019-09-03T15:07:02Z</updated>
	<published>2011-09-01T03:50:16Z</published>


	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;So after our early start we headed for Novosibirsk and the road was fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made a wrong turning getting into &lt;strong&gt;Lenina&lt;/strong&gt;, the place to hang about and
ended up having to cross the river Ob (strangely the same name as &quot;water&quot; in
Persian) again and I was furious. Traffic was pretty awful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, after that navigation blunder (google maps routing does not work here)
we did find parking and we nervously checked into Centralnaya Hotel.
Centralnaya looked like a typical Soviet hotel and it is. However it&#39;s the best
run hotel of its kind. Its a little dear, but those of us who have had
nightmares staying in similar looking hotels should try this. Everything works.
Including Internet. And it has a fantastic central location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then had a leisurely lunch at &quot;Pechki Lavochki&quot;, an excellent Russian
restaurant a few doors up. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/6099029161/&quot;&gt;food was
great&lt;/a&gt; and it was just so
awesome not to be in some shithole for lunch or eating Ramen (again) on the
road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2004 I took this photo of Novosibirsk&#39;s theatre&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/73378159/&quot; title=&quot;dcp_8932 by Kai Hendry, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm1.static.flickr.com/34/73378159_24f3d7211e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;332&quot; alt=&quot;dcp_8932&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again in 2011, the roads are better and the roof is looking good. Otherwise,
nothing has changed drastically like Kazakhstan, which personally I find
comforting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/6101624231/&quot; title=&quot;Largest theatre in Russia by Kai Hendry, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm7.static.flickr.com/6085/6101624231_93e5833b9f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;374&quot; alt=&quot;Largest theatre in Russia&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/hendry/73378480/&quot;&gt;Kas&lt;/a&gt;, a friend of Ivan
who hosted &lt;a href=&quot;https://delaunay.org/antoine/&quot;&gt;Antoine&lt;/a&gt; and I when we toured the
region in 2004, met Jamie and I, team Geekout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He asked us lots of questions about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theadventurists.com/the-adventures/mongol-rally&quot;&gt;Mongol
Rally&lt;/a&gt;, and like my
other journalist friend in Kazakhstan, seemed to have little idea that 300 or
so teams are gallivanting across their backyard!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later his colleague met with us from their &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ngs.ru/&quot;&gt;Novosibirsk news
site&lt;/a&gt;, asking us about our impressions of the town, since
not many tourists come here. Tbh I think Novosibirsk has a lot going for it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&#39;s on the trans-siberian railroad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&#39;s not an overbearing city like Moscow or St. Petersburg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great Russian food can be found here&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Best Jazz club in the world here, Tuba&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing you have a host or contact, they treat you like gold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of students and there is some nearby science town&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a lot of good conversation with Kas, his wife &amp;amp; colleague, Jamie and I
wound up in the said Novosibirsk Jazz institution to see some remarkable
impromptu performances by locals. Fantastic stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we are taking it easy since from this point on, it&#39;s camping.
I&#39;ve now booked my flight out for the 12th to see my
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/juttahendry/&quot;&gt;sister&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/rcfl&quot;&gt;girlfriend&lt;/a&gt;.  Jamie is off on the 10th. So
we have &lt;em&gt;9 days&lt;/em&gt; to reach &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ulan_Bator&quot;&gt;Ulan
Bator&lt;/a&gt;, else Jamie misses his flight
back home to dreary London.  Wish us luck!&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Novosibirsk/#comments" type="text/html" />


	<link rel="comments" href="/posts/Novosibirsk/comments.atom" type="application/atom+xml" />

</entry>

</feed>
